<herbal>
	<item>
		<name>Buñga</name>
		<sci_name>Areca alba||Areca catechu||Areca cathechu||Areca hortensis||Bin lang</sci_name>
		<common_name>Areca nut (Engl.)||Boa (Ilk., It., Ign.)||Bua(Ibn., Pang.)||Buñga (Tag.)||Dapiau (Iv.)||Hua (It.)||Lugos (sul.)||Luyos (Pamp.)||Pasa (Yak.)||Takobtob (Bik.)||Va (Ital.)||Areca nut palm (Engl.)||Betel nut palm (Engl.)||Betel quid (Engl.)||Ta Fu-p´i (Chin.)||Bin lang zi (Chin.)</common_name>
		<vernacular>ARABIC: Fûfal, Fofal, Kawthal, Tânbûl.||ARMENIAN: Arygn.||BURMESE: Kunthi Pin Kun||CHINESE: Da fu zi||DUTCH: Arecanoot, Arecapalm, Betelnoot, Betelnootpalm, Betelpalm, Pinangboom, Pinangnoot.||FINNISH: Arekapalmu.||FRENCH: Aréquier, Noix D´arec, Noix De Bétel.||GERMAN: Arekanuss, Arekapalme, Betelnüsse, Betelnuß Palme, Betelpalme||GUJARATI: Sopaadii, Topaarii||HINDI: Supaadii, Supaarii, Supari.||INDIA: Supari.||ITALIAN: Areca, Avellana D´india, Noce Del Betel, Noce Di Arec, Noce Di Betel, Palma Arec.||JAPANESE: Areka Yashi, Binrou, Binrouju.||KHMER: Phla, Sa la.||MALAY: Kavugu, Pinang, Pinang Sirih, Pokok Pinang, Pucuk (Indonesia).||NEPALESE: Supaarii||PERSIAN: Popal.||PORTUGUESE: Areca Catecú, Arequeira, Arequiera, Noz De Areca, Noz De Bétele.||RUSSIAN: Areka Katekhu, Arekovaia Pal´ma, Betel´naia Pal´ma, Pal´ma Katekhu.||SINHALESE: Puwak.||SPANISH: Areca, Bonga, Nuez De Areca, Nuez De Betel, Palma Catecu.||SWEDISH: Betelnöt, Betelpalm.||TAMIL: Bakkumaroma, Kamugu, Kathakambu||THAI: Khet, ma, mak, Mak Mia, mak Mu, mak Song.||URDU: Supaadii.</vernacular>
		<properties>Areca nut is the fourth most commonly used psychoactive substance in the world, chewed regularly by at least 10% of the population, with high prevalences in South and Southeast Asia. Bunga is an erect, solitary tree growing to 25 meters high, and marked with annular scars. Leaves about 3 to 4 meters long with numerous leaflets, 60 to 90 centimeters long, the upper ones confluent. Spadix is much branched and compressed, with the branches filiform above, bearing very numerous, somewhat distichous male flowers which are yellow and about 5 millimeters long. Female flowers are at the base of the branches and in axils, about 1 centimeter long or more. Fruits are ovoid, smooth, orange or red when ripe; 4 to 6 centimeters long, with a somewhat fleshy pericarp and fibrous mesocarp.</properties>
		<usage>In the Philippines, the buyo is regarded as tonic and general stimulant, but harmful with excessive use which can cause loss of appetite, salivation, and general degeneration of the organism.||Fruit in decoction considered abortifacient, the nut as an emmenagogue.||Tender seeds used as purgative; grated ripened ones as vermifuge. Externally used as astringent.||Sprains, bruises, contusions - Crush leaves, mix with a little coconut oil, warm and apply on affected area.||Tooth whitener: Carbonize and powder a kernel and rub on teeth.||Tapeworm infestation: 1 glassful of 5% decoction as enema to be retained for one hour. Also, decoction of kernels boiled 20-30 minutes; for less than 12 years of age, 6 kernels (30 g); over 12 years old, 10-12 kernels (50-60 g); for adults, 16-18 kernels (80-90 g). The bunga may be mixed with kalabasa, boil for 1 hour, maintaining 2-glass volume for oral intake.||In excess, nuts can cause vomiting and diarrhea; intoxicating to some.||Young nut is useful in bowel complaints. Tincture used as astringent gargle, and when diluted with water, useful for bleeding gums and may be used for stopping water discharges from the  vagina. It is also used for stopping the pyrosis (heartburn) of pregnancy.||Dried nut is stimulant, astringent and taeniafuge. It increases the flow of saliva; sweetens the breath, strengthens the gums and produces mild exhilaration.||Fruit in decoction considered abortifacient.||In Ayurvedic medicine, the nut is used for headaches, fever and rheumatism.||In China, used to treat parasitic infection. Also, used for dyspepsia, constipation, beriberi and edema. The bark is used for choleraic affections, for flatulence, dropsical and obstructive diseases of the digestive tract.||Ointment made from finely powdered catechu and lard used for chronic ulcerations.||In southern India, dried fruits are powdered and heated with coconut oil and applied topically on burns.||Fruit mixed with juice of Commelina benghalensis and stem juice of Canna indica and applied topically on wounds||In Malaya, young green shoots are used as abortifacient in early pregnancy.||In India, juice of young leaves mixed with oil is used externally for lumbago. Also used for urinary disorders and reported to have aphrodisiac properties.||In traditional medicine n India, nut used in treating skin ulcers.||In Keral and Tamil Nadu states of India, nut extract is a popular remedy for migraine headaches.||In the rural areas of Dakshima, Kannada, husk fibers are used for cleaning teeth.||In India and China the areca nut has been used as anthelmintic since time immemorial.||In the Materia Medica of ancient China, the betel nut is considered masticatory, dentrifice, and vermifuge.||In Indo-China, Punjab, and Cashmere, the kernel of the fruit is one of the constituents of the general masticatory of the East - the "betel" or pan.</usage>
		<availability>Wild-crafted</availability>
	</item>
</herbal>