<herbal>
	<item>
		<name>Araro</name>
		<sci_name>Maranta arundinacea||Maranta indica||Maranta protracta||Maranta ramosissima||Maranta sylvatica||Maranta variegatum</sci_name>
		<common_name>Araro (Tag.)||Araru (Ibn., It,, Tag.)||Aroru (Tag.)||Aruru (Tag.)||Bai (Iv.)||Galamaka (Bon.)||Sagu (Bik., Ilk.)||Uraro (Tag.)||Arrowroot (Engl.)||Maranta (Engl.)||Obedience plant (Engl.)||Zhu yu (Chin.)</common_name>
		<vernacular>DANISH: Salepmaranta.||DUTCH: Pijlwortel, Salepwortel.||FRENCH: Arrowroot des Antilles, Dictame (Antilles), Herbe aux flèches, Maranta arundinacée.||GERMAN: Pfeilwurz.||HINDI: Tikhor, Tikkor.||JAPANESE: Kuzuukon, Maranta.||MALAY: Garut, Ubi bemban, Ubi garut, Yaitu garut (Indonesia).||PORTUGUESE: Agutiguepa, Araruta-comum, Araruta-especial, Araruta- palmeira, Aru-aru.||RUSSIAN: Maranta trostnikovaia, Maranty trostnikovoi.||SANSKRIT: Tavaksiri, Tugaksiri.||SPANISH: Ararú, Araruta, Caña flecha, Chuchute tamalera, Guape, Guate, Jamachipeke, Jamaichepeque, Juájuá, Juá-juá, Maranta, Rizoma de maranta, Sagú, Sagú de San Vicente, Saguero, Silú, Sucu, Sulú, Shimipampana, Tacea, Tamalera, Tubérculo de maranta, Yerén, Yuquilla.||TAMIL: Aruruttukkilangu, Kukai niru.||VIETNAMESE: Dong c?.</vernacular>
		<properties>Araru is an erect, smooth, dichotomously branched herbaceous perennial plant 1 - 2 meters high, growing from fleshy, fusiform rootstocks. Stems are slender. Leaf blades are lanceolate, attenuate-acuminate, 10 to 20 centimeters long, thin petioled, green and rounded at the base. Inflorescence is terminal, lax, divaricate, and few-flowered. Flowers are white, about 2 centimeters long.</properties>
		<usage>In the West Indies, roots used for poulticing poisoned and other wounds.||Mashed roots as plaster applied to areas of insect stings and spider bites.||Applied to the skin to soothe painful, irritated and inflamed mucous membranes.||Roots also poulticed for poisoned wounds.||The fresh juice is used as antidote for vegetable poisons.||Used to soothe the stomach and as a remedy for diarrhea, probably from its high starch content.</usage>
		<availability>Wild-crafted.||Cultivated for arrowroot starch.</availability>
	</item>
</herbal>