<herbal>
	<item>
		<name>Agas-moro</name>
		<sci_name>Vernonia cinerea||Vernonia vialis||Conyza cinerea||Conyza chinensis||Eupatorium luzoniensis||Ye xiang niu</sci_name>
		<common_name>Agas-moro (Ilk.)||Bulabod (Sub.)||Kolong-kugon (S.L. Bis.)||Magmansi (Pang.)||Sagit (Bon.)||Tagulinai, tagulinay (Tag.)||Tagulinau (Tag.)||Sahadevi (India||Ironweed (Engl.)||Ash coloured Fleabane (Engl.)||Ji se cao (Chin.)</common_name>
		<vernacular>CHINESE: Jia xian xia cua, Xiao shan hu, Ran se cao, Suo gai ban jiu ju, Guia gun can.||GERMAN: Kleines Eisenholz, Kleines Scheinaster||INDIA: Sahdei, Sahaderi, Sandri; Kukseem, Sadori, Naichette, Mukuthipundu, Pirina.||INDONESIA: Buyung-buyung, Sawi Langit, Lidah Anjing, Rumput ekor kuda.||JAPAN: Yambaru-higotai||LAOS: Nya Phaen Din Yen||MALAYSIA: Rumput tahi babi, Tambak-tambak, Tambak bukit.||MYANMAR: Byaing-chay-pin||NIGERIA: Bojure||PUERTO RICO: Yerba Socialista||VIETNAM: Bach Dau Ong</vernacular>
		<properties>Agas-moro is an erect, slender, sparingly branched, somewhat pubescent annual herb, growing up to 20 to 80 centimeters high. Leaves, smaller at higher altitudes, are oblanceolate to obovate, 2 to 6 centimeters long, with pointed or obtuse tips, with shallowly toothed margins. Heads are small, stalked, borne in open, lax corymbs, and about 7 millimeters long and 2.5 millimeters in diameter. Flowers are rather bright-purple, all perfect, the corolla all equal, tubular, slender 5-lobed, about 20 in each head, twice as long as the involucral bracts which are linear and silky. Fruits are achenes, striate, ribbed or angled; pappus hairs numerous.</properties>
		<usage>In the Philippines infusion of plant taken internally for cough.||Plant also used for wounds.||Decoction of leaves used against humid herpes, eczema, etc.||Used for colds and fever; also for acute jaunditic hepatitis.||Plant decoction used by Hindus to promote perspiration in febrile affections.||Combined with quinine, used for malarial fevers.||Expressed juice of plant used for hemorrhoids.||In Chuta Nagpus whole plant used as remedy for bladder spasms and strangury.||Root given for dropsy.||Flowers used for conjunctivitis; also reported useful for fevers.||In Patna, leaves employed as alexipharmic and anthelmintic.||In the Nighantas plant used for asthma, bronchitis, and consumption.||Neurasthenia, insomnia, night urination among infants, infected sores, mastitis, snake bites, sprains, furuncle.||Dosage: 15 to 30 gms dried material (among infants, 9 to 15 gms), 30 to 60 gms fresh material in 				  decoction.||Poultice of fresh material used for eczema, carbuncle and snake bites.||In India, whole herb juice is used most frequently – for eye problems. Also used for poisonous insect and snake bites. As a tonic, taken twice a month with milk. For ringworm, applied to affected parts with milk. Used for all types of fever and considered one of the best remedies for typhoid.||In India seeds used for cough, flatulence, intestinal colic. Paste of seeds with lime juice used to treat pediculi. Flowers used for conjunctivitis, rheumatism, fever.||In Ayurveda, used for consumption, asthma, bronchitis and fevers.||In Senegal and French Guinea plant infusion used to wash newborn infants; also used for children with incontinence of urine.||Bitter root used as vermifuge.||In Ceylon, used for wounds and sores; taken internally to promote sweating.</usage>
		<availability>Wild-crafted</availability>
	</item>
</herbal>