<herbal>
	<item>
		<name>Takip-kohol</name>
		<sci_name>Centella asiatica||Hydrocotyle asiatica</sci_name>
		<common_name>Hahanghalo (C. Bis.)||Panggaga (Sub.)||Pispising (Bon.)||Tagaditak (Iv.)||tu kola||Takip-kohol (Tag.)||Takip-suso (Tag.)||Taingan-daga (Tag.)||Tapiñgan-daga (Tag.)||Yahong-yahong (S-L. Bis.)||Chi-hsueh Ts´ao (Chin.)||Indian Hydrocotyle (Engl.)||Pennyworth (Engl.)||Spade leaf (Engl.)||Tiger grass (Engl.)</common_name>
		<properties>Takip-kohol is a prostrate, creeping, sparingly hairy or nearly smooth perennial herb, with delicate and slender stems rooting at the nodes. Leaves are rounded to reniform, 2 to 5 centimeters wide, horizontal, more or less cupped, rounded at the tip, and kidney-shaped or heart-shaped at the base, palmately veined, margins undulate-crenate, the rounded lobes often overlapping. Petioles are erect, 3 to 20 centimeters long. Flowers are dark-purple, axillary, ovate, and about 1 centimeter long. Peduncles occur in pairs or threes, less than 1 centimeter long and usually bear 3 sessile flowers. Fruits are minute, ovoid, white or green, and reticulate, each with 9 subsimilar longitudinal ridges. Carpels are five, cylindric compressed, about 2.5 millimeter long, white or green, reticulate. Ovary is inferior. Stamens are 5, epigynous.</properties>
		<usage>In the Philippines, sap of leaves used as curative for sclerotic wounds.||Decoction of leaves used as diuretic and considered useful for gonorrhea.||Useful in the treatment of chronic and obstinate eczema. Also prescribed for secondary and tertiary syphilis accompanied by gummatous infiltration and ulceration, in chronic and callous ulcers, as a stimulant in infantile diarrhea and eczema and abscess, and in chronic rheumatism.||Leaves are toasted and given as infusion in bowel complaints and fevers of children. Also applied as anti-inflammatory to areas of blows and bruises.||Seeds used for dysentery, fever, and headache.||Infectious hepatitis, measles, respiratory tract infections - colds, tonsillitis, laryngopharyngitis, bronchitis.||Fresh material: 60 to 260 gms, dried material: 30 to 60 gms: Take in form of decoction.||Counterirritant: Pound fresh leaves, mix with vaseline or oil and apply over affected area as poultice.||Wounds and sore: The sap of the leaves is used on wounds and skin sores. Also, on chaps, scratches and 		  	  superficial burns.||In many folkloric systems, used for tuberculosis, syphilis, dysentery, hypertension, venous extremity problems and common cold.||In India and Fiji, roots used for skin inflammation, to improve blood circulation, to treat bloating, congestion and depression.||Also considered to be a brain and memory stimulant, used for Alzheimer´s disease and senility.||In Ayurvedic and Chinese medicine, used for depression and anxiety.||In Sri Lanka and Madagascar, used for a variety of mental and neurological problems.||In India and Africa, used for leprosy, hypertension and cancer.||Worldwide, herb believed to improve memory and enhance concentration.</usage>
		<availability>Wild-crafted.||Tinctures, capsules, extracts in the cybermarket.</availability>
	</item>
</herbal>