<herbal>
	<item>
		<name>Pakong parang</name>
		<sci_name>Pteris mutilata||Pteris crenata||Pteris ensiformis</sci_name>
		<common_name>Buntot-kapon (Tag.)||Pakong-buntot(Tag.)||Pakong kapon (Tag.)||Pakong- parang (Tag.)||Asian brake (Engl.)||Slender brake (Engl.)||Sword brake fern (Engl.)</common_name>
		<properties>Pakong-parang has creeping rhizomes, sparingly clothed with adpressed scales. Stipe (fern "stem") of fertile fronds are 5 to 10 cm long; those of the sterile fronds longer, 10 to 30 cm long; pale, glabrous and fascicled (growing in dense tufts). Fronds are thin and glabrous, 10 to 30 cm long, with very few pinnae; sterile fronds are shortest, 5 to 15 cm broad, with the lowest or all lateral pinnae pinnate, with few sharply serrate, oblong lateral pinnules, 7 to 10 mm wide; the fertile fronds with pinnae correspondingly forked instead of pinnate, the segments longer, linear and 4 to 8 mm wide. Sori are on the lower surface of the leaflets, along the margins in a dense uninterrupted row which does not extend to the apex. Sori protected by a reflexed membranaceous projection of the margin.</properties>
		<usage>In Pahang, juice of young fronds used as astringent for cleansing unhealthy tongues of children.||Root juice used as application for glandular swellings of the neck.||Decoction of fresh fronds drunk by dysenteric patients.||Bacillary dysentery, enteritis, fever, malaria, swelling and painful throat: 30 to 60 gms dried material in decoction.||Urinary tract infection, leucorrhea: 30 to 60 gms dried material in decoction.||Mumps, measles, eczema: apply as poultice.||Used to control menstruation in Bougainvelle.||In New Guinea, fronds applied to boils, ulcers and arrow wounds; also used to control menstruation.||A decoction of Eclipta prostrata and Pteris ensiformis used for hemorrhoidal bleeding, dysentery and enteritis.||In Vanuatu, for dysmenorrhea, a handful of leaf fronds are rubbed over the abdominal area.</usage>
		<availability>Wild-crafted.</availability>
	</item>
</herbal>