<herbal>
	<item>
		<name>Asparagus</name>
		<sci_name>Asparagus officinalis||Asparagus officinalis||Asparagus polyphyllus</sci_name>
		<common_name>Asparagus (Tag., Engl.)||Common asparagus (Engl.)||Lu sun (Chin.)</common_name>
		<vernacular>AFRIKAANS: Aspersie.||ARABIC: Halgun, Kishk almaz.||BOSNIAN: Kukovina, Mekostruk, Šparoga.||BULGARIAN: Asperzhi||COUNTRY: Shi diao bai||CROATIAN: Beluš, Pitome šparoge, Pitomi sparog, Šparga, Špargle, Šparoga, Šparogama, Šparugama.||CZECH: Chrest obecný, Chrest lékarský.||COUNTRY: Almindelig asparges, Asparges, Rodstok af asparges.||DUTCH: Asperge, Wortelstok van asperge.||ESTONIAN: Aspar, Harilik aspar.||FINNISH: Parsa, Ruokaparsa.||FRENCH: Asperge, Asperge alimentaire, Asperge commune, Asperge officinale.||GERMAN: Garten-Spargel, Gemüse-Spargel, Spargel, Wurzelstock vom Spargel.||GREEK: Sparaggi, Sparagi.||HEBREW: Spragus, Asparag refui.||HINDI: Shatwaar.||HUNGARIAN: Spàrga, Közönséges spárga.||ITALIAN: Asparagio, Asparago, Asparago comune.||JAPANESE: Asuparagasu, Matsubaudo, Oranda kiji kakushi.||KOREAN: A seu pa ra geo seu, Yakpijjaru.||NEPALESE: Kurilo.||ORWEGIAN: Asparges.||PERSIAN: Maarcube.||POLISH: Szparag lekarski.||PORTUGUESE: Aspargo, Espargo, Espargo hortense, Rebentos de espargos.||ROMANIAN: Sparanghel.||RUSSIAN: Asparagus lekarstvennyi, Sparža, Sparža aptecnaja.||SERBIAN: Betrica, Kalenac, Kolenac, Kuka, Kuke, Kukovina, Sparga, Špargla, Šparožina, Vilina metla.||SLOVAKIAN: Asparágus lekársky, Špargla.||SLOVENIAN: Beluš, Navadni beluš, Smerecica, Špargelj, Šparglin, Vrtni beluš, Vrtni špargelj.||SPANISH: Brote de espárrago, Esparraguera, Espárrago común, Esparrago.||SWEDISH: Sparris, Vanlig sparris.||THAI: Normai farang.||TURKISH: Kuskonmaz.||URDU: Asparagys.||VIETNAMESE: Mang tây</vernacular>
		<properties>Asparagus is an erect, unarmed, branched herbaceous perennial herb, growing up to 1 meter in height. Leaves (scales) are very minute, and the cladodes (branchlets) fascicled, slender terete, 0.5 to 1.5 centimeters long. Flowers are axillary, fascicled, solitary or in pairs, pedicelled, the perianth straw-yellow or greenish yellow, about 5 millimeters long. Fruit is globose, 6 to 10 millimeters in diameter, fleshy red when ripe.</properties>
		<usage>Green resin used for flatulence, calculous affections, cardiac dropsy, rheumatism, and chronic gout.||Given in doses of 1 to 2 grains, combined with potassium bromide, for cardiac dropsy and chronic gout.||Water in which asparagus was boiled, although disagreeable, is good for rheumatism.||In Brazil, roots considered a powerful diuretic.||Roots also used for bronchial catarrh and pulmonary tuberculosis.||In Tehran, roots are burned and smoked to relieve toothaches.||Rhizome is used as cardiac sedative, palliative, diuretic, and laxative.</usage>
		<availability>Wild-crafted.||Extracts in the cybermarket.</availability>
	</item>
</herbal>