<herbal>
	<item>
		<name>Abukado</name>
		<sci_name>Persea gratissima||Persea americana||aurus persea||E li</sci_name>
		<common_name>Abukado (Tag.)||Abokado (Ceb.)||Aguacate (Span.)||Alligator pear (Engl.)||Avocado (Engl.)||You li (Chin.)</common_name>
		<vernacular>BURMESE: Htaw bat.||CHINESE:Zhang li, Huang you li, Lao li, Xi yin du lao li.||CROATIAN : Americhki avokado.||DANISH: Avocado, Avogatpære.||DUTCH: Advocaat.||FRENCH: Avocat, Avocatier.||GERMAN: Alligatorbirne, Avocado, Avocadobaum, Avocadobirne, Avocato-Birne.||HUNGARIAN: Avokado.||ITALIAN: Avocato.||JAPANESE: Abokado, Perusea.||KHMER: ´avôkaa.||KOREAN: Ah bo k´a do.||MALAY: Adpukat, Avocad, Aviokad, Bash apukaod, Buah mantega, Buah apokat.||NORWEGIAN: Avokado.||PORTUGUESE: Abacate, Abacateiro.||RUSSIAN: Avokado.||SPANISH: Aguacate, Cura, Cupandra, Devora, Okh, Palta, Sikia||THAI: Awokhado.||VIETNAMESE: Bó, Lê daù.</vernacular>
		<properties>Abukado is a medium-sized tree reaching a height of up to 10 to 15 meters. Leaves are alternate, leathery, oblong to oval or obovate, about 20 centimeters long. Flowers are small, yellow, borne in naked, panicled hairy cymes. Stamens are 12, in groups of 3 in 4 whorls. Fruit is large, fleshy, elongated, of various sizes and shapes, often resembling a pear, 8 to 18 centimeters long, some weighing as much as two kilos, soft and edible, with a nutty flavor, color varying from yellow-green to purple.</properties>
		<usage>The pulp is thought to promote menstruation.||The pulp is used to hasten the suppuration of wounds.||The pulp is considered aphrodisiac and emmenagogue.||Ointment from pulverized seeds sometimes employed as cavity of the tooth to relieve toothaches.||The leaves and bark promote menstruation; the tea has been used to expel worms.||Used for diarrhea and dysentery.||Rheumatism and neuralgia: Pulverize seeds or bark, mix with oil and apply on affected area as counterirritant.||Beverage: Take decoction of leaves as tea.||Pulp is applied to shallow cuts, prevents infection.||Flesh of ripe fruit is soothing to sunburned skin.||In different parts of the world, has been recommended for anemia, exhaustion, high cholesterol, hypertension, gastritis and duodenal ulcers. The leaves have been reported effective as antitussive, antidiabetic, antiarthritic and antiinflammatory.||In Mexico, rind of the fruit used as anthelmintic. In the form of a liniment, used in intercostal neuralgia. Seeds, crude or toasted, are used to treat skin rashes, diarrhea, asthma, hypertension, rheumatism, and dysentery caused by helminths and ameobas.||In many African countries used in traditional medicine for gastritis, gastroduodenal ulcers, hypercholesterolemia, hypertension, anemia.||In Nigeria, seed extracts used for hypertension.</usage>
		<availability>Seasonal fruiting and ubiquitous market produce.</availability>
	</item>
</herbal>