<herbal>
	<item>
		<name>Bael</name>
		<sci_name>Aegle marmelos||Belou marmelos||Crataeva marmelos||Cydonia indica||Feronia pellucida</sci_name>
		<common_name>Bael (Tag.)||Bael fruit (Engl.)||Bengal quince (Engl.)||Bitter orange (Engl.)||Elephant´s apple (Engl.)||Japanese bitter apple (Engl.)||Maredoo (Engl.)||Stone apple (Engl.)||Wood apple (Engl.)||Mu ju (Chin.)</common_name>
		<vernacular>ARABIC : Safargal hindî, Safarjal e hindî, Shull.||ASSAMESE: Bel.||BENGALI: Bel.||BURMESE : Opesheet, Ohshit.||CHINESE: Meng jia la ping guo, Ying pi ju, Yin du gou qi.||FRENCH : Bel indien, Cognassier du Bengal, Coing de l´Inde, Oranger de Malabar, Oranger du Malabar.||GERMAN : Belbaum, Bengalische Quitte, Indische Quitte.||GUJARATI: Bel, Belli, Bili.||HINDI: Bel, Beli, Belgiri, Bila, Bilin, Shil, Shul, Siphal, Sirphal, Shriphal, Vilva, Willaw, Willau.||HUNGARIAN : Bengálibirs.||ITALIAN : Cotogno del Bengala, Cotogno d´India.||JAPANESE: Berunoki, Igure marumerozu.||KANNADA: Baelada mara, Belpatra, Bilva, Maaluraa.||KHMER : Bnau, Phneou, Pnoi.||LAOTIAN : Toum.||MALAY: Bel, Bila, Bilak, Maja (Indonesia), Maja batuh (Indonesia), Maja pahit (Indonesia), Modjo (Java).||MALAYALAM : Maaredy.||MARATHI: Bel, Vel.||NEPALESE: Bel, Belapatra, Belpatra.||ORIYA : Belo.||PERSIAN : Bah hindi shull.||POLISH : Klejowiec jadalny.||PORTUGUESE : Marmelos de Bengala, Marmeleiro de India.||SANSKRIT : Bilva, Bilwa, Shivadrumaa, Shivaphala, Vilva,Vilvam.||SINHALESE: Be li.||SPANISH : Bela, Milva.||-TAMIL: Kuuviram, Vilvama, Vilvam , Vilva marum.||TELUGU: Bilva, Bilva pandu, Maaredu, Kapitthaphalamu, Velagapandu.||THAI: Matum, Mapin.||TURKISH : Hind ayva agh.||URDU : Bel, Bel kham, Belgiri.||VIETNAMESE : Bau nau, Tráimam.</vernacular>
		<properties>Bael is a small, deciduous, smooth tree. Spines are straight, strong, axillary, and about 2.5 centimeters in length. Leaflets are 3 to 5, ovate-lanceolate, shallowly toothed, the lateral ones being sessile and the terminal ones long-petioled. A gummy sap exudes from the wounded branches, hanging down in long strands, slowly hardening. Flowers are 3 centimeters across, greenish-white and sweet-scented. Fruit is nearly spherical, 10 to 14 centimeters in diameter. Rind is grey or yellow; the pulp sweet, thick, aromatic, gelatinous, and orange-colored. Seeds are numerous, oblong and flat.</properties>
		<usage>Mucous fluid from the stem and fruit is rubbed on the hair in place of oil by the rural folk.||Decoction of root-bark used for hypochondriasis, melancholia, intermittent fever, palpitations.||Poultice of leaves applied to inflamed parts.||Bitter fresh juice, diluted with water, used as remedy for catarrh and fever.||Decoction of leaves used for asthma.||Fresh juice of leaves, sweetened with honey, used as laxative or febrifuge; also, used for asthma.||Sweet-scented extract from flowers used as lotion for the eyes.||Infusion of flower used as cooling drink.||Unripe or half-ripe fruit used for diarrhea, believed effective because of the tannins and mucilaginous substances.||Hindu physicians used a confiture made from preserved sliced fruits for diarrhea and dysentery.||Sherbet drink of ripe fruit - two ounces of pulp in 3 or 4 ounces of water or syrup - is a pleasant laxative and a simple cure for dyspepsia.||Bael-marmalade or an aromatized confection is a useful breakfast during convalescence from dysentery or diarrhea; also, used daily as a preventive during cholera epidemics. Also, used to prevent the growth of piles.||Fruit used in tuberculosis.||Leaf paste applied to premature graying hair.||Leaves said to cause abortion and sterility in women.||Decoction of unripe fruit mixed with fennel and ginger is used for hemorrhoids.||Astringent rind of the ripe fruit used in acute dysentery, its effect enhanced by combining it with opium.||Powder of dried pulp used in dysentery accompanied by gripping pains in the loins and costiveness.||Tonic is prepared from 12 to 15 gm of the powdered pulp; 16 to 20 grains as febrifuge; 20 grains to 2 drachms, as nauseant and antidysenteric.||In Iranian folk medicine, used for treatment of diabetes.||In Indian traditional medicine, used for diarrhea.</usage>
		<availability>Wild-crafted.</availability>
	</item>
</herbal>