<herbal>
	<item>
		<name>Parol-parolan</name>
		<sci_name>Cardiospermum halicacabum</sci_name>
		<common_name>Alalayon (C. Bis.)||Bangkolan (Tag.)||Kana (Bis.)||Layaw (Tag.)||Lobo-lobohan (Tag.)||Paltu-paltukan (Pamp.)||Paria-aso (Ilk.)||Parol-parolan (Tag.)||Paspalya (Ilk.)||Heart pea (Engl.)||Heart seed (Engl.)||Ballon vine (Engl.)||Love-in-a-puff vine (Engl.)||Showy baloon vine (Engl.)||Smooth leaved heart pea (Engl.)||Tao ti ling (Chin.)</common_name>
		<vernacular>CHINESE: Dao di ling, Feng chuan ge, Jin si ku lian teng, Ye ku gua, Bao fu cao.||FRENCH: Coeur des Indes, Pois de coeur.||INDONESIAN: Ketipes, Pari gunung, Cenet.||MALASIAN: Peria buian, Uban kayu, Bintang berahi.||THAI: Kok kra om, Pho on, Luupleep khruea.||VIETNAMESE: T[aaf]m phong, Ch[uf]m phong.</vernacular>
		<properties>Parol-parolan is a slender, herbaceous, more or less hairy vine, 1 to 3 meters in length.
		Leaves are trifoliate, and 5 to 9 centimeters long. Leaflets are ovate to lanceolate, and 1 to 5 centimeters long, with coarsely toothed or lobed margins. Flowers are small, white, and about 2.5 millimeters long. Sepals are 4, concave, the outer ones small. Petals are 4, two larger ones usually adhering to the sepals and with an emarginate scale above the base, the smaller 2 ones distant from the stamens. Stamens are 8, eccentric, filaments free or connate at the base. Ovary is 3-celled, style 3-fid, ovules solitary. Fruits are inflated, obovoid, 1.5 to 2.5 centimeters long, somewhat triangular and 3-keeled. Seeds are round and black, with a prominent, white, heart-shaped aril at the base.</properties>
		<usage>In the Philippines, decoction of roots used as diaphoretic, and used for catarrh of the bladder.||Leaves are used internally as a beverage as an anti-rheumatic; externally applied as oil embrocations.||Cold, fever, renal edema, urinary tract infections.||Furuncle, carbuncle, eczema.||Sprains and external wounds.||Dosage: use 12 to 15 gms dried material or 15 to 30 gms fresh material in decoction. Pounded fresh material may be used as poultice, decoction of fresh material may be used as external wash.||Elsewhere, poultice of leaves used for rheumatism, swellings, orchitis, and dropsy.||Used as a hair wash.||Leaf juice used for earaches or meatal discharges.||Plant used as diuretic, stomachic, rubefacient, cholagogue, and pectoral.||Decoction of root and leaves used for rheumatism, nervous diseases, piles, chronic bronchitis, and phthisis; also used for amenorrhea.||In Sindh, roots used as diaphoretic, diuretic, and aperient. Decoction of roots used for piles and amenorrhea. ||Roots used as emetic and laxative.||Fried leaves are applied to the pubis to increase menstrual flow in amenorrhea.||Leaves boiled in castor oil applied for rheumatism, pains, swellings, tumors of various kinds.||In the Malabar coast, leaves are used for pulmonary complaints.||In Martinique, leaves are used as diuretic and stimulant.</usage>
		<availability>In Ayurveda, used for rheumatism, fever and earache.</availability>
	</item>
</herbal>