<herbal>
	<item>
		<name>Kauayan-tinik</name>
		<sci_name>Bambusa spinosa||Bambusa spinosa||Bambusa blumeana||Bambusa pungens||Bambusa arundo||Bambusa arundinacea||Bambusa teba||Le zhu</sci_name>
		<common_name>Aonoo  (Bik.)||Batakan (Bis.)||Baugin (Pamp.)||Dugian (Bik.)||Caña espina (Span.)||Kaaono (Bis.)||Kauayan (P. Bis., Bon., C. Bis., Bik., Ilk, Tag.)||Kauayan-gid (P. Bis.)||Kauayan-ñg-bayog (Ilk.)||Kauayan-potog (Sbl.)||Kauayan-sitan (Ilk.)||Kauayan-tinik (Tag.)||Kauayan-totoo (Tag., Bik.)||Kabugauan (Bik.)||Lamnuan (Is.)||Marurugi (Bik.)||Pasiñgan ((Ibn.)||Paua (Bis.)||Rugian (Bik.)||Giant thorny bamboo (Engl.)||Spiny bamboo (Engl.)||Thorny bamboo (Engl.)||Yu zhu (Chin.)</common_name>
		<vernacular>CHINESE: Ci zhu, Ci ce zhu.||FRENCH: Bambou épineux.||JAPANESE: Shi chiku.||KHMER: Rüssèi roliëk.||LAOTIAN: Phaix ba:nz.||PORTUGUESE: Bambu-espinoso||SPANISH: Cana espina||SUNDANESE: Haur cucuk.||THAI: Mai si suk, Phai si suk.||VIETNAMESE: Tre gai, Tre la nga.</vernacular>
		<properties>Kauayan-tinik is an arborescent bamboo, occasionally shrubby or scrambling. Rhizomes are short-necked. Stems are 10 to 25 meters high, 8 to 15 centimeters in diameter, the basal parts surrounded by stiff, branched, interlaced, spiny branches. Leaves are 10 are 20 centimeters long, 1 to 2 centimeters wide. Rarely flowering. Panicles are large. Spikelets are slender, compressed and 2 to 3 centimeters long.</properties>
		<usage>Decoction of leaves as emmenagogue, to induce lochia after childbirth.||Decoction (20 gms for 1 liter of water; 3 cups daily) of stems of young shoots applied externally for inflamed joints.||Decoction of leaves used to stimulate menstruation; also used for intestinal worms.||Poultice of young shoots used for dislodgement of worms from ulcers.||Bud of leaf used in leprosy, fevers, and hemoptysis.||Decoction of roots used for anuria.||Roots given as a specific for eruptive affections.||Stems and leaves used for treatment of blood diseases, biliousness, leucoderma, inflammations, wounds and piles.||Roots applied to ringworm and bleeding gums.||ecoction of shoots taken for respiratory ailments.||Juice of flower instilled to ear for earache.||Poultice of tender shoots used for cleaning wounds. Decoction or juice of leaves applied to wounds.||Decoction of tender shoots used as abortifacient in the first month and in the last month, to induce labor, and to facilitate placental expulsion.||In India, decoction of leaves used for diarrhea.</usage>
		<availability>Cultivated||Wild-crafted.</availability>
	</item>
</herbal>