<herbal>
	<item>
		<name>Pandakaki-puti</name>
		<sci_name>Alstonia pacifica||Ervatamia benthamiana||Ervatamia pandacaqui||Tabernaemontana mindanaensis||Tabernaemontana mindorensis||Tabernaemontana pandacaqui||Tabernaermontana orientalis||Tabernaermontana laurifolia||Tabernaemontana semperflorens||Tabernaemontana cumingiana||Tabernaemontana lurida</sci_name>
		<common_name>Agtimaloi (Buk.)||Alibotbot (P. Bis.)||Alibutbut (Pamp., Bis., Bik.)||Busbusilak (Ilk.)||Halibutbut (Bik.)||Kampupot (Tag.)||Kudibetbet (Ig.)||Kukabulau-buntai (Ibn.)||Kuribetbet (Ilk.)||Pandakaki (Tag., Bis., Pamp.)||Pandakaki-puti (Tag.)||Pandaya (Bik.)||Sakang-manuk (Bik.)||Salibukbuk (P. Bis.)||Salimbabaya (C. Bis.)||Talanisog (Bik.)||Toar (Bik.)||Tunkal (P. Bis.)||Banana bush (Engl.)||Windmill bush (Engl.)||Jian guo gou ya hua (Chin.)</common_name>
		<properties>Pandakaki is an erect, branched and smooth shrub, 1 to 4 meters high. Leaves are elliptic-lanceolate to oblong-elliptic, 5 to 12 centimeters long, narrowed at both ends, shining and short-stalked. Inflorescences are axillary and terminal, peduncled, and have rather few flowers. Calyx is green, ovoid, and short. Corolla is white, tinged with green, slender-tubed, 1.7 centimeters long and slightly enlarged upward; limb is 2 to 2.5 centimeters in diameter, composed of five, spreading, falcate, lanceolate lobes. Follicles are red or yellowish-red, oblong, 2 to 4 centimeters long, and longitudinally ridged or keeled.</properties>
		<usage>In the Philippines, leaves used as cataplasm on the belly to induce menstruation.||For eczema: Boil 3 cups of chopped leaves in one gallon of water for 10 minutes; add 2 gallons of hot water.||Fresh leaves are fried in oil and applied to itchy skins lesions for symptomatic relief.||Leaf juice applied for wound healing.||Hot Foot Baths: A local immersion bath covering the feet, ankles and legs used for a variety of conditions: To relieve head, chest and pelvic congestion; to stop nosebleeds; to relieve spasms and pains of feet and legs; to induce sweating; to relieve menstrual cramps and headaches.||Poulticed leaves applied on the abdomen to hasten childbirth.||Erectile dysfunction: In Tiaong, reportedly used as "herbal viagra." Boil 15-25 leaves in 3 glasses of water for 10 minutes; drink the decoction. (Note: Like many of the herbal medicines touted as "herbal viagra," kampupot use is rural folkloric with no known scientific or pharmacologic basis for its claim.)||Decoction of root and bark used for a variety of stomach and intestinal ailments.||The white sap of the stem is applied to thorn injuries and to hasten the surfacing of the thorn fragment.||In Thailand, roots used to treat fever, pain and dysentery.</usage>
		<availability>Wild-crafted.</availability>
	</item>
</herbal>