<herbal>
	<item>
		<name>Saging</name>
		<sci_name>Musa paradisiaca||Musa sapientum||Musa rosacea||Da jiao</sci_name>
		<common_name>Banana (Engl.)||Kela (Hindi)||Saging (Tag., C. Bis.)||Platano (Span.)||Fen ba jiao (Chin.)</common_name>
		<vernacular>BURMESE: Taw nget byaw.||FRENCH: Banane cultivée, Bananier des sages, Bananier commun.||GERMAN: Adamsfeige, Dessertbanane, Jamaicabanane, Obstbanane.||ITALIAN: Banana comune, Banano comune, Fico d&quot;Adamo.||JAPANESE: Banana.||MALAY: Biu, Cau, Gedang, Puti, Kulo, Pisang.||SPANISH: Banana, Bananeira, Guineo, Plátano.||TAMIL: Vaazhai, Vaazhaipoo (flower).||TELUGU: Arati, Artipandu, Kadala.||THAI: Kluai.</vernacular>
		<properties>The banana plant is the largest herbaceous flowering plant. The main or upright stem is actually a pseudostem, growing from a corm, to a height of 6 to 7.6 meters. Leaves are spirally arranged, as long as 2.7 meters and 60 cm wide, fragile and easily torn by wind, with the familiar frond look. Each pseudostem produces a single bunch of bananas; the pseudostem dies after fruiting, as offshoots usually develop from the base of the plant. Each pseudostem produces a single inflorescence, the banana heart, containing many bracts between rows of flowers. The banana fruits develop from the heart, in a hanging cluster made up of tiers (hands), up to 20 fruit to a tier.</properties>
		<usage>Young leaves used for cool dressing of inflamed and blistered surfaces and as cool application for headaches.||Powdered roots used for anemia and cachexia.||Mucilage prepared from seeds used for catarrhal and mild inflammatory forms of diarrhea.||Juice of tender roots used as mucilage for checking hemorrhages from the genitalia and air passages.||In China, juice of roots used as antifebrile and restorative.||Juice of the trunk applied to scalp to increase hair growth and prevent hair from falling.||In West Africa, used for diarrhea.||In Gambia, sap of inflorescence used for earaches.||In French Guiana, flowers used as emmenagogue.||In the Gold Coast, sap from roots given as enema for diarrhea.||In Cambodia, Java and Malaya, juice from trunk used for dysentery and diarrhea.||Juice from flowers, mixed with curds, for dysmenorrhea and menorrhagia.||Flour made of green bananas used for dyspepsia with flatulence and acidity.||Ripe fruit, mixed with half its weight in tamarinds and a little salt, is a valuable food in chronic dysentery and diarrhea.||Cooked flower used for diabetes. Flowers also used as cardialgic.||Sap of the flower used for earaches.||In Western Ghat in India, leaves are used for bandaging cuts, blisters and ulcers.||Ripe bananas combined with tamarind and common salt used for dysentery.||In traditional medicine in India, used for diabetes.||In South-Western Nigeria, green fruits used for diabetes.</usage>
		<availability>Wild-crafted and commercial cultivation.||Tinctures and capsules in the cybermarket.</availability>
	</item>
</herbal>