<herbal>
	<item>
		<name>Himbabalod</name>
		<sci_name>Eugenia acutangula||Botryoropis luzonensis||Stravadium luzonense||Barringtonia luzonensis||Barringtonia reticulata||Barringtonia spicata||Barringtonia acutangula</sci_name>
		<common_name>Apaling (Ig.)||Himbabalod (P. Bis.)||Kalambudya (Ilk.)||Latuba (Ibn.)||Putad (Tag.)||Putat (Tag., Pamp., Bik.)||Sako (Mbo.)||Saku (Mbo.)||Topuk (Mag.)||Tuba (Tag., Ibn.)||Barringtonia (Engl.)||Cut nut (Engl.)||Indian oak (Engl.)||Wild almond (Engl.)</common_name>
		<properties>Himbabalod is a smooth tree growing to a height of 12 meters. Bark is dark brown, rough, 10 to 12 millimeters thick. Leaves are somewhat crowded at the end of the branches, oblong-obovate, 6 to 14 centimeters long, pointed at the ends, the young leaves finely toothed at the margins. Flowers are numerous, axillary and pendulous racemes, 10 to 40 centimeters long. Fruit is oblong-ovoid, 3 to 4 centimeters long, about 1.5 centimeters thick, bluntly quadrangular, pointed at the ends, and crowed by persistent calyx lobes.</properties>
		<usage>In the Philippines, bark decoction used as stomachic.||Bark also applied to wounds.||In Amboina and India, root and bark used for wounds.||Juice of leaves used for diarrhea.||In Sindh, fruit is used for coughs, colds, and asthma.||Seeds are used as aromatic in colic and parturition, also for ophthalmic.||Kernels are powdered, mixed with butter and sago, for diarrhea.||In Bombay, kernels are used as emetic.||Powdered seeds are used as snuff for headache.||Seeds of the fruit, rubbed with the juice of fresh ginger, for nasal catarrh and to expel flatus in colic.||Rubbed with water on the chest to relieve pains and colds, to the abdomen to relieve colic and flatulence.||In India, fruits and leaves in alkaline decoction for abdominal and splenic disorders.||Seeds rubbed down on stone and applied over sternum for chest colds.||A few grains mixed with the juice of fresh ginger, taken internally, induce vomiting or help the expulsion of mucus.||Fruit incorporated in antiseptic ointment for venereal sores.||Juice of leaves for mucoid diarrhea.||Fruit used as anthelmintic and as astringent in gingivitis.||Decoction of bark used as mouthwash in gum problems.||In Sri Lanka, used for malaria.||German Commission E monograph recognizes the bark for use in common colds, cough, bronchitis, fever and diarrhea.</usage>
		<availability>Wild-crafted.</availability>
	</item>
</herbal>