<herbal>
	<item>
		<name>Makahiya</name>
		<sci_name>Mimosa asperata||Mimosa pudica||Han xiu cao</sci_name>
		<common_name>Babain (Ilk.)||Damohia (Tag.)||Dilgansusu (Ilk.)||Harupai (S. L. Bis.)||Huya-huya (Bis.)||Kiromkirom (S. L. Bis.)||Makahia (Pang., Tag.)||Sipug-sipug (Sub.)||Tuyag-huyag (P. Bis.)||Torog-torog (Bik.)||Bashful mimosa (Engl.)||Humble plant (Engl.)||Sensitive plant (Engl.)||Shame plant (Engl.)||Tickle-Me plant (Engl.)||Pa chou cao (Chin.)</common_name>
		<vernacular>BENGALI : Laajak, Lajjavathi.||CHINESE : Pa chou cao, Zhi xiu cao, Hu he cao||DANISH : Almindelig mimose.||DUTCH : Kruidje-roer-me-niet.||FINNISH : Tuntokasvi.||FRENCH : Mimeuse commune, Mimeuse pudique, Sensitive.||GERMAN : Gemeine Mimose, Sinnpflanze.||HINDI : Chuimui, Lajaalu, Lajjavanthi, Lajouni.||ITALIAN / SWEDISH : Sensitiva.||SANSKRIT : Khadiraka, Lajjalu, Namaskaar, Namaskaari, Raktapaadi, Samangaa, Shamipatra.||SPANISH : Dormidera, Sensitiva, Vergonzosa.||TAMIL : Tottalavaadi.||TELUGU : Attaapatti.</vernacular>
		<properties>Makahiya is a diffusely spreading, half-woody herb, with branched stems up to 1 meter long, sparingly prickly with numerous deflexed, bristly hairs. The leaves are very sensitive, both pinnae and leaflets, folding when touched. Pinnae are usually 4, digitately arranged at the end of each petiole, and 4 to 9 centimeters long. The leaflets are narrowly oblong, inequilateral, 1 to 1.5 centimeters long, sessile, sparingly bristly, with pointed tips. Heads are long-peduncled, solitary or 2 to 3 in each axil, about 1 centimeter in diameter. Pods are flat, slightly recurved, 1 to 2 centimeters long, with 3 to 5 one-sided joints that fall away on maturity. Florets are red in the upper part with pink to lavender filaments.</properties>
		<usage>In the Philippines, roots used as diuretic; also used for dysentery and dysmenorrhea.||Entire plant in decoction used as alterant and antiasthmatic.||Root considered aphrodisiac, and used for bladder gravel and similar urinary complaints.||Decoction or infusion of leaves used in asthma; expectorant.||Used for hypertension, menorrhagia, glandular swelling, sore throat and hoarseness.||Powdered seeds applied to wounds and sores.||Bruised leaves applied to bruises.||Decoction of leaves used for diabetes.||Powdered roots and leaves taken with milk for piles and fistula.||Juice applied externally to fistulous sores.||Poultice of leaves for glandular swellings.||Leaves and roots used for piles and fistula.||Used as antifertility agent in some parts of India.||1:1 ethanol water extract used for pain relief.||Seeds used a coffee substitute.||In China, used for treatment of anxiety and depression.||In Ayurveda, used as antiasthmatic, aphrodisiac, analgesic and antidepressant; also used in diseases associated with corrupted bile and blood, bilious fever, piles, jaundice, leprosy, ulcers, and small pox.||In India, used for birth control.||In the Antiles, Guiana, and La Reunion, roots used vomitive.||In Indo-China, seeds used as emetic.||In Mexico, used to alleviate depression.||In Punjab and Cashmere, seeds used for sore throat.||In Concan, paste of leaves applied to hydrocoeles and glandular swellings.||Infusion of leaves used for dysentery; also as bitter tonic.||Roots used for leucoderma, vaginopathy, metropathy, ulcers, dysentery, inflammations, jaundice, asthma, small pox, strangury, fevers.||Leaves used for hydrocoele, hemorrhoids, fistula, scrofula, conjunctivitis, wounds and hemorrhages.||Whole plants used for bladder calculi; externally, for edema, rheumatism, myalgia and uterine tumors.||Whole plant, crushed, used for itching and scabies.</usage>
		<availability>Wild-crafted.||Tinctures, seeds, extracts in the cybermarket.</availability>
	</item>
</herbal>