<herbal>
	<item>
		<name>Apoi-apoian</name>
		<sci_name>Gynandropsis gynandra||Cleome gynandra||Gynandropsis pentaphylla||Cleome alliacea||Cleome alliodora||Cleome pentaphylla||Pedicellaria pentaphylla||Sinapistrum pentaphyllum</sci_name>
		<common_name>Apoi-apoian (Tag.)||Balabalanoian (Tag.)||Halaya (P. Bis.)||Hulaya (P. Bis.)||Tantandok (Ilk.)||Tantandok-a-dadakel (Ilk.)||Spider flower (Engl.)||Bastard mustard (Engl.)||Cat´s whiskers (Engl.)||Yang jiao cai (Chin.)</common_name>
		<vernacular>CAMBODIAN: MOMIENH.||CHINESE: Bai huo cai, Pe hua tsai.||CUBAN: Volantin.||EGYPTIAN: Abu quam, Arareeg, Tamaleekah, Tokshangeth.||ETHIOPIA: Boekbeha, Gargama.||FRENCH: Mousambe.||GERMAN: Senfkapper, Benzoinbaun, Fieberstrauch.||INDONESIAN: Babowan, Enceng-enceng, Mamang, Langsana, Merah, Boboon, Ent jengent, Leug-tengan.||KENYAN: Chinsaga, Saget, Keyo, Mikabili, Mwangani, Mwianzo, Kisiat, Akio luni.||LAOTIAN: Sienz.||NETHERLAND: Kattesnor.||SOUTH AFRICAN: Tameleika, Akaki, Agyiri, Ziri.||VIETNAMESE: M[af]n m[af]n tr[aws]ng.</vernacular>
		<properties>Apoi-apoian is an erect, branched, somewhat hairy herb, growing 0.4 to 1 meter high, usually with purplish stems. Leaf has a very long petiole with five leaflets. Leaflets are obovate or oblong-obovate, 2 to 5 centimeters long, pointed at the base, more abruptly pointed at the tip. Flowers are borne in racemes which terminate the branches, showy and somewhat spidery in appearance. Sepals are lanceolate, green, about 4 millimeters long. Petals are white or tinged with purple, 1 to 1.2 centimeters long, withe elliptic to obovate blades. Fruit is a cylindric capsule, 4 to 10 centimeters long, about 5 mm in diameter, containing numerous, small, dark-brown seeds.</properties>
		<usage>Bruised leaves used as counterirritant or revulsive.||Leaves used externally as the seeds of mustard, and taken internally for certain bilious disorders.||Whole plant made into an ointment applied to pustular eruptions of the skin; simply boiled in oil, used - for cutaneous diseases, especially leprosy.||In Indo-China, used as antiscorbutic.||Bruised leaves used as rubefacient and vesicant, producing copious exudation, providing relief obtained from blister without its inconveniences.||Shangaans used the pounded leaf as counterirritant in rheumatism, neuralgia, headache, stiff neck, taking care to withdraw the application before it produces a blister.||Leaf juice used occasionally for earache, otorrhea, and other ear affections.||Root decoction used as mild febrifuge.||Decoction of seeds used as wash for piles, rheumatism and malarial disorders.||Seeds are febrifuge and applied locally for headaches.||In Africa, leaves are crushed for a concoction to drink as scurvy cure. In other communities, leaves are boiled and marinated in sour milk to become a nutritious meal, believed to improve eyesight, provide energy, and cure marasmus. Also, highly recommended for pregnant and lactating women. Also, used in the treatment of bronchitis, boils, earaches and nasal congestion and as eyewash.</usage>
		<availability>Wild-crafted.</availability>
	</item>
</herbal>