<herbal>
	<item>
		<name>Guazuma</name>
		<sci_name>Guazuma tomentosa||Guazuma tomentosa||Guazuma guazuma||Guazuma ulmifolia||Theobroma tomentosa</sci_name>
		<common_name>Guazuma (Engl.)||Bastard cedar (Engl.)||Musket tree (Engl.)||Pigeon wood (Engl.)</common_name>
		<vernacular>BENGALI: Nipaltunth.||FRENCH : Bois de hêtre, Bois d´orme, Bois d´homme, Hêtre gris, Hêtre orme (Eastern Caribbean), Hêtre vert, Mahot-baba (Eastern Caribbean), Mahot-hêtre (Eastern Caribbean), Mahot-hetre, Orme d´amérique.||GUJARATI: Bhadraksha, Khoto rudraksha.||HINDI: Rudraksha.||JAPANESE: Guazuma, Guazuma urumiforia, Nireba guazuma, Teoburaama guazuma.||KANNADA: Rudrakshi.||MALAYALAM: Rudraksham.||MARATHI: Rudrakshi.||PORTUGUESE: Araticum-bravo, Buxuma, Cabeça-de-negro, Camacan, Cambá-aça, Embira (Brazil), Embireira, Embiru, Enveira du campo, Fruta-de-macaco, Guaxima-macho, Guaxima-torcida, Mutamba, Mutamba, Mutamba-verdadeira, Mutambo, Mutambu, Pau-de-bicho, Pau-de-montanha, Pau-de-pomba, Periquiteira, Piriquiteira, Pojó.||SANSKRIT: Rudraksha.||SPANISH: Guacima, Ajilla, Ajya, Aquiche, Bacedar, Bolaina, Bolaina negra, Cabeza de Negro, Cablote, Caca de mico, Cambo-aca, Caulote, Chicharron, Coco, Contamal, Cualote, Guacima, Guácima, Guácimo blanco, Guácimo cimarrón, Guácimo de ternero, Guácimo dulce, Guazima, Guazuma, Majagua de toro, Nocuana-yana, Papayillo, Parandesicua, Tablote, Tapaculo, Vácima, Yaco granidillo, Yaco de venado.||TAMIL: Rudrasam, Tenbachai, Thenmaram, Tubakki, Tuppakki maram.||TELUGU: Bhadraksha, Rudraksha.</vernacular>
		<properties>Guazuma is a tree growing to a height of 10 or more meters. Leaves are oblong to broadly ovate, 4 to 16 centimeters long, with pointed tip, rounded to heart-shaped base, and toothed margins. Flowers are small, yellowish-green or whitish, sweet-scented, and borne in axillary cymes. Fruit is a woody capsule, nearly spherical or oval, 2 to 4 centimeters long, covered with black tubercles resembling those of a mulberry, and imperfectly 5-valvate at the apex. Seeds are numerous in each cell.</properties>
		<usage>Bark and other plant parts used for malaria, cutaneous and syphilitic affections, elephantiasis, afflictions of the chest and leprosy.||Bark and other plant parts used for malaria, cutaneous and syphilitic affections, elephantiasis, afflictions of the chest and leprosy.||In the West Indies, the inner bark is used for elephantiasis; also as a sudorific.||In the Antilles, the bark is mucilaginous and used for astringent applications.||Fruit is considered pectorant and used for bronchitis.||Beverage of crushed seeds soaked in water used for diarrhea, dysentery, cold, coughs, contusions and venereal disease. Also, used as diuretic.||Used as topical remedy for hair loss and baldness.|| Reported use by Latino healers in NYC for uterine fibroids.</usage>
		<availability>Wild-crafted.||Seeds, powders, teas, tinctures in the cybermarket.</availability>
	</item>
</herbal>