<herbal>
	<item>
		<name>Kandikandilaan</name>
		<sci_name>Stachytarpheta indica||Verbena indica||Verbena jamaicensis||Stachytarpheta cayennensis</sci_name>
		<common_name>Albaka (P. Bis.)||Bilu-bilu (Sul.)||Bolo-moros (Bik.)||Kalintigas (Tag.)||Kandikandilaan (Tag.)||Limbagat (C. Bis.)||Verbena de las Antilla (Span.)||Aaron´s rod (Engl.)||Bastard vervain (Engl.)||Blue porterweed (Engl.)||Blue vervain (Engl.)||Blue snakeweed (Engl.)||Brazilian tea (Engl.)||Devil´s coach whip (Engl.)||Rat tail (Engl.)||Verbena cimarrona (Span.)||Wild verbena (Engl.)||Jia ma bian (Chin.)</common_name>
		<properties>Kandikandilaan is an erect and branched half-woody plant, 1 to 1.5 meters high. Stems are terete, the younger ones slightly angled. Leaves are elliptic to oblong-ovate, 2.5 to 10 centimeters long, with pointed tips and toothed margins, the base decurrent on the petiole. The spikes are terminal, rather slender, 10 to 30 centimeters long, 3-4 millimeters thick, green and continuous. Calyx is small, oblique, and 4-toothed. Corolla is deep blue, 1 centimeter long, The fruit is enclosed in the calyx, appressed to and somewhat sunk in the rachis, smooth, oblong, and about 4 millimeters long.</properties>
		<usage>Decoction or roots are abortive.||Decoction of leaves are vermifuge to children.||In the Antilles, juice of fresh leaves is emetocathartic.||Decoction of leaves in enemas used to expel intestinal worms; also used as purging vehicle for other vermifuges.||Infusion of roots has been used for gonorrhea.||Triturated fresh leaves used on ulcers. Used as maturative cataplasm for boils.||Bruised leaves rubbed on sprains and bruises.||In Brazil, used for coughs, fever, to expel worms and promote menstruation; as a diuretic and laxative. Also used for rheumatism.||In the West Indies, used to expel worms.||Creoles use the leaf tea for dysentery.||In North Nigeria, decoction used for dysentery. Also used as vermifuge.||In Peru, used for diabetes.||In Cuban herbal medicine, used as an abortive.||In immigrant Haitian communities in Cuba, an infusion made from three whorls or tops of S. jamaicensis is used for children in the morning on an empty stomach as an anthelmintic.||In traditional medicine, leaves and stem extracts used to prepare drugs for use as stomach tonic, for dyspepsia, allergies, asthma, fevers and liver problems. Externally, used for ulcers, sores, cuts and wounds.</usage>
		<availability>Wild-crafted.</availability>
	</item>
</herbal>