<herbal>
	<item>
		<name>Boto</name>
		<sci_name>Scaevola frutescens||Scaevola koenigii||Scaevola lobelia||Scaevola sericea||Lobelia frutescens||Lobelia taccada||Cao hai tong</sci_name>
		<common_name>Balak-balak (Tag.)||Bokabok (Tag., Bis.)||Bosboron (Tag., Bis.)||Boto (Tag., Bis.)||Chalmalukung (Ilk.)||Dudukdukin (Ilk.)||Hulbo (Bik.)||Linu (Tag.)||Linog (Sbl.)||Marokborok (Tag.)||Mosboron (Tag., Bis.)||Panabolong (Tag., Bis.)||Pañgangtolon (Tag., Bis.)||Tagustus (Bis.)||Scaevola (Engl.)||Beach naupaka (Engl.)||Sea lettuce tree (Engl.)</common_name>
		<vernacular>INDONESIA: Dudulan, babakoan, subong-subong||MALAYSIA: Ambong-ambong, Buas-buas laut, akar pahit||PAPUA NEW GUINEA: Gavagava, Pahop.||THAILAND: Bong bong, Rak thale, Ho raa.||VIETNAM: H[ees]p, S[ow]n, d[uw][ow]ng.</vernacular>
		<properties>Boto is a large, spreading shrub with loose bark and a stout stem and branches. Leaves are crowded in the axil, alternate, obovate or obovate-oblong, 12 to 25 centimeters in length, 6 to 10 centimeters or more wide, and silky, with an obtuse tip which tapers to a wedge-shaped base. Flowers are white, tinged with purple, about 2.5 centimeters long, and borne in considerable numbers in axillary cymes. Calyx-lobes are linear-lanceolate, 3 to 6 millimeters long, and obtuse and enlarged in fruit. Corolla-tube is 1.5 to 1.8 centimeters long, obliquely split to the base behind, narrow, and hairy; the lobes lanceolate, and 6 to 8 millimeters long. Fruit is a drupe, ovoid, somewhat rounded, 1 to 1.5 centimeters long, longitudinally ridged and very succulent.</properties>
		<usage>In the Philippines, juice of ripe fruit used for cleaning opacities of the eyes.||Decoction of roots used for beriberi and certain syphilitic affections; also for dysentery.||In Amboina, juice of fruit is instilled by natives into the eyes to clear opacities and improve dimness of vision.||As a cataplasm, fruit is used for tumors; internally, induces menstruation.||In India, decoction of leaves and bark used for tachycardia.||Used as diuretic; also, as remedy for dropsy.||Bitter leaves eaten to relieve indigestion.||Poultice of leaves applied to headaches, tumors and swollen legs.||Cataplasm of fruit applied to tumors; taken internally to induce menstruation.||Root decoction used for dysentery and certain syphilitic affections.||Juice of berries instilled on eyes to clear opacities; used for dimmed vision.</usage>
		<availability>Wild-crafted.</availability>
	</item>
</herbal>