<herbal>
	<item>
		<name>Paraiso</name>
		<sci_name>Melia azedarach||Melia azedarach||Melia chinensis||Melia azedarach||Melia japonica||Melia toosendan</sci_name>
		<common_name>Paraiso (Span., Tag.)||Bead tree (Engl.)||Cape syringa (Engl.)||China berry (Engl.)||Chinese umbrella tree (Engl.)||Indian lilac (Engl.)||Pride of India (Engl.)||K&quot;u Lien (Chin.)</common_name>
		<vernacular>AFRIKAANS: Bessieboom, Bessieboom syringa, Maksering.||ASSAMESE: Ghora nim.||BENGALI: Bakarjam.||CATALAN: Mèlia.||CHINESE: Lian, Ku lian, Lian shu, Zi hua shu, Sen shu, Chuan lian zi, Jin ling zi.||CROATIAN: Melija, Očenašica.||CZECH: Zederach hladký.||DANISH: Paternostertræ.||DUTCH: Kralenboom.||FRENCH: Acacie d&quot;Égypte, Adrézarach, Arbre à chapelets, Arbe margousier, Azédarac, Azédarach, Cascarelle, Cormier des indes, Lilas de Perse, Lilas des Indes, Margousier, Mélie Pater-noster.||GERMAN: Chinesischer Holunder, Indianischer Lilak, Indischer Zederachbaum, Indischer Zedrachbaum, Paternosterbaum, Persischer Flieder, Zedrachbaum.||GREEK: Agriopaschaliá, Louloudiá, Moschokarfia, Paschaliá, Pseudomelia, Solomós.||HINDI: Bakain, Bakānā nīmba, Bakayan, Mahanimb.||ITALIAN: Albero da rosari, Albero dei rosari, Albero dei paternostri, Lillà delle Indie, Perlaro.||JAPANESE: Sendan.||KANNADA : Bevu.||KHMER: Dâk&quot;hiën, Sadau khmaôch.||KOREAN: Meol gu seul na mu.||LAOTIAN: H&quot;ienx, Kadau s&quot;a:ngz.||MALAY : Gringging, Marambung, Mindi, Mindi kecil .||MALAYALAM : Malaveppu.||MARATHI: Bakan nimb.||NEPALESE: Bakenu, Khaibasi.||PERSIAN: Zanzalakht||POLISH: Miotla.||PORTUGUESE : Amargoseira, Amargoseira-do-Himalaio, Árvore-santa, Cinamomo, Conteira, Lilás-da-Índia, Lilás-das-Índias, Margoseira-do-Himalaio, Mélia, Paraíso, Sabonete-de-soldado.||SANSKRIT: Mahanimbah.||SPANISH : Agriaz, Agrión, Árbol de los rosarios, Arbol del para, Árbol del Paraíso, Árbol santo, Azedaraque, Cinamomo, Flor del paraiso, Melia, Paraíso, Paraíso sombrilla, Piocha, Rosariera.||SWEDISH : Zedrak.||TAMIL: Kattu vembhu, Malai vembu, Malaivenimpu.||TELUGU: Kali yapa, Kondavepa, Turakavepa, Turka vepa.||THAI: Hian, Lian, Lian bai yai, Khian, Krian.||TURKISH: Tespih aǧacı.||URDU: Bakain, Dharek, Dhrek.||VIETNAMESE : Cây xoan, Sâ dông.</vernacular>
		<properties>Paraiso is a shrub or small tree, usually not more than 3 to 4 meters high. Leaves are bipinnate, occasionally tripinnate, 20 to 40 centimeters long. Leaflets are numerous, oblong-ovate, toothed, and 4 to 7 centimeters long. Flowers are fragrant, 5-parted, borne on panicles 10 to 20 centimeters long. Petals are about 1 centimeter long, oblong-spatulate, and pale lilac, while the staminal-tube is usually dark purple and about 7 millimeters long. Fruit is ovoid or subglobose, about 1 centimeter long.</properties>
		<usage>Root decoction or fluid extract used as anthelmintic.||Root bark used as vermifuge; also used for intermittent fevers and dysentery.||Root bark used in America as a cathartic and emetic.||In India, before quinine, root bark used for malaria.||Infusion of bark used as febrifuge especially for periodic fevers; also, for thirst and nausea.||Poultice of bark used in leprosy and scrofulous ulcers.||Leaves used in a variety of forms - poultice, wash, ointment or liniment - as external applications to ulcers and skin diseases||Crushed leaves used as poultice for boils and sores.||Internally, infusion of fresh leaves used as a bitter vegetable tonic and alterative. (The stools noticed to become a brilliant yellow after use.) Infusion also used for chronic malarial fevers; and as a powerful alterative for chronic syphilitic infections.||Decoction of leaves used for ; also, for hysteria.||Juice of leaves used internally as anthelmintic, antilithic, diuretic, and emmenagogue.||Decoction of leaves used as astringent, anthelmintic and stomachic.||In Sidh, poultice of leaves used for sprains.||Paste of flowers used to destroy headlice and associated scalp eruptions. Also, used for prickly heat.||Poultice of flowers and leaves applied for nervous headaches.||Fruit used as purgative and emollient; useful for intestinal worms, urinary affections and piles.||Fruit is considered both tonic and poisonous, and used for leprosy and scrofula; the fruit pulp used as anthelmintic. (The pulp of the fruit, mixed with grease, is reported to kill dogs.)||Seeds are emetic, laxative and anthelmintic; in Indo-China, used for typhoid fever and urinary retention.||Oil used for syphilitic sores and indolent ulcers; also, for leprosy, suppurating scrofulous glands and rheumatism.||Oil used as application for erysipelas, scrofula, and various skin diseases; also, as parasiticide in various cutaneous affects as ringworm and scabies.||Internally, the oil used for chronic malarial fevers, syphilis, and leprosy.||In Ayurveda, used for leprosy, inflammation, cardiac disorders and scrofula; as antihelmintic, antilithic, diuretic.||In Mauritius, the root bark is used as anthelmintic; in Algeria, as tonic and antipyretic; elsewhere, the heartwood is used to relieve asthma, as emetic or as emmenagogue.</usage>
		<availability>Wild-crafted.</availability>
	</item>
</herbal>