<herbal>
	<item>
		<name>Dadayem</name>
		<sci_name>Bidens pilosa||Bidens sundaica||Bidens leucorrhiza||Bidens odorata||Gui zhen cao</sci_name>
		<common_name>Anguad (Ig.)||Burbutak (Tag.)||Dadayem (Iv.)||Nghuad (Tag.)||Ñguad (Tag.)||Pisau-pisau (C. Bis.)||Puriket (Bon.)||Beggar ticks (Engl.,)||Water marigold (Engl.)||Spanish needles (Engl.)||Black jack (Engl.)||San ye gui zhen cao (Chin.)</common_name>
		<vernacular>CHINESE: Zhan ren cao, Xie qian cao, Dui cha cao, Dou zha cao, Jin kai zhan pan||FIJIAN: Batimadramadra, matakaro, matua kamate, mbatikalawau, mbatimandramandra||FRENCH: Bident hérissé, herbe d&quot;aiguille, somet.||HAWAIIAN: kī, kī nehe, kī pipili, nehe||INDONESIA: Ajeran, hareuga, jaringan, ketul||JAPANESE: Ko-sendangusa||MALAYSIAN: Kancing baju, pali-pali pasir, kerotan||MAORI: Kamika tuarongo, nīroa, piripiri, piripiri kerekere, piripiri nīroa||PUKAPUKAN: Pilipili||SPANISH: Acetillo, arponcito, bidente piloso, cacho de cabra, masquia, papunga chipaca, pega-pega.||TAHITIAN: Piripirti||THAILAND: Puen noksai, kee nok sai, yaa koncham khaao||TONGAN: fisi&quot;uli||VIETNAM: D[ow]n bu[oos]t, t[uwr] t[oo] hoang.||WALLISIAN: Tae puaka</vernacular>
		<properties>Dadayem is an erect, branched, usually more or less hairy herb, 0.2 to 1.5 m high. Leaves are 1- to 2-pinnatifid and 15 cm long or less, the upper ones being usually much smaller; segments ovate-lanceolate, 2 to 5 cm long and toothed. Flowering heads are about 8 mm long. Disc flowers are brown or yellowish and the ray ones yellow or nearly white. Inner involucral bracts have broad, scarious margins. Flowering head about 8 mm long. Fruits are achenes, black, long and slender, linear, 1 to 1.5 cm long and characterized by four projections at the apex.</properties>
		<usage>Used as preventive for influenza or cold, used for treatment of swelling pain at the throat, fever among infants, fear of cold weather.||For sore eyes, pounded leaves are applied over the eyelids.||Used for poisonous insects and snake bite.||For enteritis, flatulence, diarrhea, appendicitis.||For sprains, contusions, chronic ulcers.||Used to stop wound bleeding.||Leaves used for treatment of thrush and candida.||For piles, chronic ulcers, various skin diseases.||Dosage: use 30 to 60 gms of dried material or 90 to 150 gms fresh material in decoction. Fresh materials may be pounded and applied as poultice or boiled in water and applied as external wash.||In Uganda, the sap from crushed leaves is used to speed up blood clotting in fresh wounds. Leaf decoction used for headaches. Plant sap is used for ear infections. Decoction of leaf powder for kidney ailments. Plant decoction used for flatulence.||In Java, Malaya and Indo-China, the leaves are used for eye complaints.||In Indo-China, dried flower buds and ground and mixed with alcohol, and used as mouthwash in toothache.||In Java, heated leaves are applied to boils to facilitate ripening.||In southern Africa, used for malaria.||In Zimbabwe, used for stomach and mouth ulcers, diarrhea and hangovers.||In Peru, leaves are balled up and applied to toothaches.||In the Amazon, used for hepatitis, angina, sore throat.||The Zulus use an enema of the powdered leaves in water for abdominal troubles. Also, flowers used as remedy for diarrhea.||In Columbia, leaves used as sudorific.||In the Congo, plant used as poison antidote and to facilitate child delivery.||In Nigeria, the powder or seed ash is used as a local anesthetic for cuts.||In Brazil, the plant is traditionally used for conditions related to cancer. Also, leaves are used as styptic to stop the flow of blood, and as vulnerary.</usage>
		<availability>Wild-crafted.</availability>
	</item>
</herbal>