<herbal>
	<item>
		<name>Kawad-kawaran</name>
		<sci_name>Cynodon dactylon||Cynodon linearis||Cynodon rufescens||Capriola dactylon||Digitaria glumaepatula||Panycum dactylon||Panicum glumaepatulum</sci_name>
		<common_name>Balbalut (Bon.)||Barutbarut (Ilk.)||Galud-galud (Ilk.)||Grama (Span.)||Kawad-kawaran (Tag.)||Kawit-kawitan (Tag.)||Kolatai (Tag.)||Palot-galot (Tag.)||Florida grass (Engl.)||Bahama grass (Engl.)||Creeping-cynodon (Engl.)||Creeping finger grass (Engl.)||Bermuda grass (Engl.)||Dog''s tooth grass (Engl.)||Dub grass (Engl.)</common_name>
		<vernacular>AFRIKAANS: Kweekgras.||BENGALI: Durba.||CAMBODIA: Smao anchien.||FIJI: Kabuta.||FRENCH: Chiendent dactyle, Chiendent pied-de-poule, Grand chiendent.||GERMAN: Hundezahngras.||HAWAII: Manienie.||HINDI: Doorva, Doob.||INDIA: Doob.||INDONESIA: Jukut kakawatan, Gigirinling, Rumput bermuda, Rumput grinting, Sukit grinting.||ISRAEL: Yablith.||KANNADA: Ambate-hullu, Graikae.||LAOS: Hnha:z phe:d.||MALAYALAM: Karuka-oulli.||MALAYSIA: Rumput minyak.||MARATHI: Doorva, Haryali.||MYANMAR: Mye-sa-myet.||NEPAL: Motie molulu, Dubo.||PORTUGUESE: Capim-bermuda.||PUNJABI: Dub, Kabbar, Talla.||SANSKRIT: Bhargavi, Doorwa, Granthi, Sveta.||SPANISH: Chepica brave, Came de niño, Pate de perdiz, Gramilla blanca.||TAMIL: Arugu, Aruvam-pillu, Mooyar-oul, Arugampull.||TELUGU: Garika, Gerike, Haryali||THAILAND: Ya-phraek.||URDU: Ghass.||VIETNAM: Cochi, Coong.</vernacular>
		<properties>Kawad-kawaran is a tropical and subtropical creeping grass with slender, branched, prostrate, usually widely creeping stems, rooting at the nodes and forming matted tufts, sending up erect, slender, flowering branches, 8 to 20 centimeters high. Leaves are 1.5 to 3 centimeters long. Spikes, numbering 3 to 4, are 2 to 5 centimeters long, narrowly linear, spreading, green to purplish. Spikelets are imbricated, about 1.5 millimeters long.</properties>
		<usage>Decoction of the entire plant used as diuretic.||In India, crushed leaves used as styptic in minor wounds to stop bleeding.||Decoction of root used as diuretic in dropsy. and syphilis.||In Sind, the roots are used as a substitute for sarsaparilla.||Infusion of root to stop bleeding from piles.||Juice of plant applied to fresh cuts and wounds.||Paste of plant applied to forehead in headaches.||Used internally for epilepsy, hysteria, bleeding in dysentery, hemorrhoids, hematuria, menorrhagia, syphilis, prostatitis.||Used for toothaches and amibiosis.||Mixed with clove (Syzygium aromaticum) used as anthelmintic.||Folk remedy for cancer, epilepsy, cough, dysentery, warts, snakebites.||In Morocco, used in treatment of kidney stones.</usage>
		<availability>Wild-crafted</availability>
	</item>
</herbal>