<herbal>
	<item>
		<name>Kamias</name>
		<sci_name>Averrhoa bilimbi</sci_name>
		<common_name>Iba (C. Bis., P. Bis., Sul., Tag.)||Ibag (Mbo.)||Ibe (Yak.)||Kamias (Tag.)||Kolonanas (Tag.)||Kolonauas (Tag.)||Kalamias (Tag.)||Kalingiwa (Bis.)||Kiling-iba (Bik.)||Pias (Ilk.)||Puis (Ig.)||Bilimibi (Engl.)||Bilimbi tree (Engl.)||Cucumber tree (Engl.)||Tree sorrel (Engl.)||Huang gua shu (Chin.)</common_name>
		<vernacular>CHINESE: Ma hu gua, Xiang yang tao.||FRENCH : Carambolier bilimbi, Cornichon des Indes, Zibeline.||GERMAN : Bilimbinaum, Gurkenbaum.||HINDI: Bilimbi.||JAPANESE: Birinbi, Nagabanogorenshi.||MALAY : Belimbing asam, Belimbing besu, Belimbing buloh, Belimbing wuluh.||RUSSIAN: Bilimbi.||SINHALESE: Bimbiri.||SPANISH : Grosella china, Pepino de Indias, Mimbro, Vinagrillo.||THAI: Tàlingpling.||VIETNAMESE : Kh? ng?t , Kh? tàu.</vernacular>
		<properties>Kamias is a small tree, growing 5 to 12 meters high. Leaves are pinnate, 20 to 60 centimeters long, with hairy rachis and leaflets. Leaflets are opposite, 10 to 17 pairs, oblong, 5 to 10 centimeters in length. Panicles growing from the trunk and larger branches are hairy, 15 centimeters long or less. Flowers are about 1.5 centimeters long, and slightly fragrant. Fruit is green and edible, about 4 centimeters long, subcylindric, or with 5 obscure, broad, rounded, longitudinal lobes.</properties>
		<usage>Skin diseases, especially with pruritus: Reduce the leaves to a paste and apply tolerably warm to areas of affected skin.||Fruit juice used as eye drops.||Post-partum and rectal inflammation: Infusion of leaves.||Mumps, acne, and localized rheumatic complaints: Paste of leaves applied to affected areas.||Warm paste of leaves also used for pruritus.||Used for boils, piles, rheumatism, cough, hypertension, whooping cough, mumps and pimples.||Cough and thrush: Infusion of flowers, 40 grams to a pint of boiling water, 4 glasses of tea daily.||For fevers, fruit made into syrup used as a cooling drink.||The fruit has been used for a variety of maladies: beriberi, cough, prevention of scurvy.||Infusion of leaves also drank as a protective tonic after childbirth.||In Malaysia, leaves are used for venereal diseases.||In Java, a conserve of fruit used for beriberi, biliousness, coughs.||In Indonesia, leaves used for boils, diabetes, mumps, fever.||In French Guyana, fruit decoction or syrup use for hepatitis, diarrhea, fever and other inflammatory conditions.</usage>
		<availability>Wildcrafted.||Seasonal fruiting.</availability>
	</item>
</herbal>