<herbal>
	<item>
		<name>Ampalaya</name>
		<sci_name>Cucumis argyl||Mormodica balsamina||Mormodica chinensis||Mormodica cylindrica||Momordica charantia||Mormodica muricata||Ku gua</sci_name>
		<common_name>Amargoso (Span.)||Ampalaya (Tag.)||Ampalia (Tag.)||Apalaya (Tag.)||Apalia (Pamp.)||Apape (Ibn.)||Apapet (Itn.)||Margoso (Tag.)||Palia (Bis., Bon., If.)||Pariu (Bik., Ilk., Sul.)||Pulia (Sub.)||Saligun (Sul.,)||African cucumber (Engl.)||Balsam apple (Engl.)||Balsam pear (Engl.)||Bitter cucumber (Engl.)||Bitter gourd (Engl.)||Tuberculated momordica (Engl.)||Liang gua (Chin.)</common_name>
		<vernacular>BURMESE: Kyethinkhathee.||CHINESE: Lai pu tao, Jin li zhi, Ku gua ye||DANISH: Balsamagurk, Balsamaeble.||DUTCH: Balsempeer.||FINNISH: Karvaskurkku.||FRENCH: Margose, Margose amère, Momordique amère, Concombre amer, Concombre africain.||GERMAN: Balsambirne, Bittergurke, Balsamgurke.||HINDI: Karela, Kerela, Tita kerala.||INDONESIAN: Paria, Pare||ITALIAN: Pomo meraviglia, Momordica amara.||JAPANESE: Niga uri, Nigai uri, Tsuru reishi||KHMER: Mreah.||LAOTIAN: Bai maha, Haix, S&quot;aix.||NEPALESE: Karelaa, Tito karelaa.||SINHALESE: Karavila, Karawila, Pakal, Pavakai.||SPANISH: Bálsamo, Calabaza africana, Cundeamor, Momordica amarga, Pepino amargo.||SWEDISH: Bittergurka.||TAMIL: Pava aki.||THAI: Maha, Mara, Phakha.||VIETNAMESE: La khoqua (leaves).</vernacular>
		<properties>Ampalaya is a climbing vine, nearly or quite smooth, annual vine. Tendrils are simple, up to 20 centimeters long. Leaves are 2.5 to 10 centimeters in diameter, cut nearly to the base into 5 to 7 lobes, oblong-ovate, variously toothed, and heart-shaped at the base. Male flower is about 12 millimeters long, and is peduncled, with a rounded, green, and about 1 centimeter long bract approximately at the middle. Female flower is yellow flower, about 15 millimeters long, long-stalked with pair of small leaflike bracts at middle or toward base of stalk. Fruit, in cultivated form, is green, fleshy, oblong, cylindric, 15 to 25 centimeters long, pointed at both ends, ribbed and wrinkled, bursting when mature to release seeds; in wild forms, ovoid, about 2 to 4 centimeters long. Seeds are oblong, compressed 10 to 13 millimeters long, and corrugated on the margins.</properties>
		<usage>In the Philippines, juice expressed from the green fruit is given for chronic colitis: also used for bacillary dysentery.||Astringent powdered leaves or root decoction can be applied to hemorrhoids.||Leaf juice for cough and as a purgative and anthelminthic to expel intestinal parasites, and for healing wounds.||Seeds also used to expel worms.||The vine or the juice of leaves used as mild purgative for children.||In large doses, the fresh juice is a drastic purgative.||Decoction of roots and seeds used for urethral discharges.||Juice of leaves used for chronic coughs.||Leaves and shoots used as vulnerary.||Sap of leaves used as parasiticide.||Fruit macerated in oil used as vulnerary.||Fruit considered tonic and stomachic; used in rheumatism, gout, and diseases of the spleen and liver.||Pounded leaves used for scalds.||Infusion of leaves or leaf juice used for fevers.||Used for chronic stomach ulcers.||Root sometimes used as ingredient in aphrodisiac preparations.||Decoction of root used as abortifacient.||Fruit in large doses considered a drastic purgative and abortifacient.||In India, root used as astringent; applied externally to hemorrhoids.||In Lagos, decoction of leaves used as stomachic.||Leaves used as anthelmintic and antipyretic, and applied externally to leprosy.||In India and Malaya, pounded leaves are applied to skin diseases, burns and scalds.||Poultice of leaves used for headaches.||Infusion of flowers used for asthma.||Olive or almond oil infusion of the fruit, without the seeds, used for chapped hands, hemorrhoids, and burns.||Root, along with fruits and seeds, used as abortifacient, as well as remedy for urethral discharges.||In Batavia, vine used as anthelmintic, purgative, and emetic.||In Jamaica, leaf decoction or infusion is taken for colds, as laxative and blood cleanser. Warm tea infusions also used for toothaches and mouth infections. Also used as a bath/wash for skin eruptions and acne.||Used for eczema, malarial, gout, jaundice, abdominal pain, kidney (stone), leprosy, leucorrhea, piles, pneumonia, psoriasis, , rheumatism, fever and scabies. Also, boiled leaves and decoction of plant used to promote lochia.||In Antilles, sweetened decoction of leaves used as emmenagogue and vermifuge.||In Cuba, used for diabetes mellitus; used for wounds refractive to other treatments, for skin disease, and for sterility in women.||In Puerto Rico, used for diabetes.||In Indo-China, fruit macerated in salted water used for fluxes, catarrh, and children&quot;s coughs. Seeds employed in the treatment of dysentery.||In Brazil, seeds used as anthelmintic.||In China, used as hypoglycemic and antidiabetic.||In Turkey, used for healing of cutaneous lesions and peptic ulcers.</usage>
		<availability>Wild-crafted.||Perennial vegetable market produce.||Tablets (Amargozin by Altermed / Pascual Laboratories) for diabetes. Recently, available in capsule formulation, Charagen Ampalaya.</availability>
	</item>
</herbal>