<herbal>
	<item>
		<name>Dalupang</name>
		<sci_name>Urena lobata||Urena lobata var. americana||Urena americana||Urena grandiflora||Urena trilobata</sci_name>
		<common_name>Afulut (Gad.)||Anonongkot (Bik.)||Bagouan (If.)||Baranggot (Bik.)||Batikil (If.)||Dalupang (P. Bis., Tag., Pamp.)||Daupang (Sul.)||Dopong (Sul.)||Kolokot (Ting.)||Kollokollot (Ilk.)||Kulot (Pang.)||Kulit (Pang.)||Kulotan (Tag., Bis.)||Kullukullut (Ilk.)||Kulut-kulutan (Tag.)||Mangkit (Ig.)||Molopolo (Tag., Pamp.)||Palisin (Tag.)||Poot-si-nuang (Is.)||Pirikit (Neg.)||Saligut (Bon.)||Supang (Sub.)||Tapanding (Mag.)||Caesar weed (Engl.)||Bur mallow (Engl.)||Congo jute (Engl.)||Di tao hua (Chin.)</common_name>
		<vernacular>CHINESE: Xiao fan tian hua, Ye mian hua, Tian fu rong, Cao mai fan tia hua, Xiao feng cao, Qian chui cao.||FRENCH: Cousin urène (Caribbean), Grand mahot-cousin (Caribbean), Jute Africain, Jute de Cuba, Jute du Congo, Jute paka, Uréna, Uréna du Brésil.||GERMAN: Kongojute.||HINDI: Bachita, Lapetua, Paka, Pathia, Unga.||PORTUGUESE: Aguaxima (Brazil), Carrapicho-de-lavadeira (Brazil), Carrapicho-redondo (Brazil), Embira (Brazil), Guaxima, Guaxima-rósea (Brazil), Malvaísco (Brazil), Malva-de-embira (Brazil), Malva-rósea (Brazil), Uaicima.||RUSSIAN: Kongolezskij dzhut, Madagaskarskij dzhut, Urena lopastnaia.||SPANISH: Aramina, Cadillo (Cuba), Malva blanca (Cuba).||VIETNAMESE: Ke hoa dao.</vernacular>
		<properties>Dalupang erect, branched shrub 0.6 to 2.5 meters high. Plant is exceedingly variable and more or less hairy, stems often with reddish branches. Leaves are pale beneath, ovate to suborbicular, 3 to 9 centimeters long, heart-shaped at the base, more or less toothed or somewhat lobed or angled, the lobes not exceeding beyond the middle of the leaf and the sinuses being usually broad and acute. Flowers are pink or purplish, about 1.7 millimeters in diameter and borne singly in the axils of the leaves, or somewhat in panicles. Petals are 5, free above, connate below and adnate to staminal tube; staminal tube truncate or minutely toothed, anthers many. Ovary is 5-celled, branches of stigma 10. Fruits are rounded but flattened and about 7 millimeters in diameter, with the 5 carpels covered with short, barbed spines.</properties>
		<usage>In the Philippines, root decoction used to relieve colic.||Infusion of root used internally as emollient and refrigerant, and externally for skin diseases associated with pain and inflammation.||Decoction of 30-60 gms of dried roots used for enteritis and dysentery, rheumatic pains, tonsillitis.||Boiled and pounded leaves used as poultice for bladder and intestinal inflammations.||Decoction of roots and leaves used to soften the skin.||In Tahiti, the plant used as emollient, and the flowers used as expectorant.||Root used externally for lumbago and rheumatism.||Decoction of seeds taken internally a vermifuge.||Poultice of fresh leaves for snake bites, sprains, and bruises.||In Nigeria used to treat diabetes.||In Malaysia, extracts of leaves and roots used to treat abdominal colic, malaria, gonorrhea, fever, wounds, toothaches and rheumatism.||In Malaysia, used for intestinal inflammation and as an emollient.</usage>
		<availability>Wild-crafted.</availability>
	</item>
</herbal>