<herbal>
	<item>
		<name>Cujete</name>
		<sci_name>Crescentia cuneiflora||Crescentia cujete</sci_name>
		<common_name>Ayale (Engl.)||Cujete (Span., Tag.)||Calabash tree (Engl.)||Kalebas (Engl.)||Hu lu shu (Chin.)</common_name>
		<vernacular>DUTCH: Kalebasboom.||FRENCH: Calebassier.||GERMAN: Kalebassenbaum.||ITALIAN: Calebassa Guiana, Icara.||PANAMANIAN: Totumo.||PORTUGUESE: Coité, Cuieira, Cuité, Cujeté.||SPANISH: Calabacero, Crescencia, Guacal, Guiro, Jicara, Morro</vernacular>
		<properties>Cujete is a smooth, much-branched tree growing to a height of 4 to 5 meters. Branches are arching with close-set clusters of leaves. Leaves are alternate, often fascicled at the nodes, oblanceolate, 5 to 17 centimeters long, glossy at the upper surface, blunt at the tip and narrowed at the base. Flowers develop from the buds that grow from the main trunk, yellowish and sometimes veined with purple, with a slightly foetid odor, occurring singly or in pairs at the leaf axils, stalked and about 6 centimeters long, and opens in the evening. Calyx is about 2 centimeters long, and split into two lobes. Fruit is short-stemmed, rounded, oval or oblong, green or purplish, 15 to 20 centimeters in diameter.</properties>
		<usage>In India, used as a pectoral, the poultice of pulp is applied to the chest.||In the West Indies, syrup prepared from the pulp used for dysentery and skin diseases; also used as pectoral.||In Rio de Janeiro, the alcoholic extract of the not-quite ripe fruit used to relieve constipation.||In Rio de Janeiro, the alcoholic extract of the not-quite ripe fruit used to relieve constipation||The bark is used for mucoid diarrhea.||Fruit pulp used as laxative and expectorant.||In the Antilles and Western Africa, fruit pulp macerated in water is considered depurative, cooling and febrifuge, and applied to burns and headaches.||In West Africa, fruit roasted in ashes is purgative and diuretic.||In Sumatra, bark decoction used to clean wounds and pounded leaves used as poultice for headaches.||Internally, leaves used as diuretic.||Throughout the Caribbean, used as analgesic and anti-inflammatory||In the Antilles, fresh tops and leaves are ground and used as topicals for wounds and as cicatrizant.||In Venezuela, decoction of bark used for diarrhea. Also, used to treat hematomas and tumors.||In Costa Rica, used as purgative.||In Cote-d&quot;Ivoire, used for hypertension because of its diuretic effect.||In Columbia, used for respiratory afflictions.||In Vietnam, used as expectorant, antitussive, laxative and stomachic. Fruit decoction used to treat diarrhea, stomachaches, cold, bronchitis, cough, asthma, and urethritis.||In Haiti, the fruit of Crescentia cujete is part of the herbal mixtures reported in its traditional medicine. In the province of Camaguey in Cuba, is considered a panacea.||In Panama, where it is called totumo, the fruit is used for diarrhea and stomachaches. Also for respiratory ailments, bronchitis, cough, colds, toothaches. headaches, menstrual irregularities; as laxative, antiinflammatory, febrifuge. The leaves are used for hypertension.</usage>
		<availability>Wild-crafted.</availability>
	</item>
</herbal>