<herbal>
	<item>
		<name>Niyog</name>
		<sci_name>Cocos nucifera||Cocos mamillaris||Palma cocos||Ye zi</sci_name>
		<common_name>Coco (Span.)||Coconut (Engl.)||Gira-gira (Sbl.)||I-ing (It.)||Iniug (Ibn.)||Lobi (S.L. Bis.)||Lubi (C.Bis., P. Bis.)||Niyog (Ilk., Bik., Bis., Ibn., Tag.)||Ngot-ñgot (Pamp., Sbl.)||Oñgot (Ibn.)||Ponlaing (Sub.)||Punlaing (Yak.)||Uñgut (Pamp.)||Ho ho yeh ji (Chin.)||Ke ke ye zi (Chin.)</common_name>
		<vernacular>ARABIC : Gawz el hind, Jauz al hind, Nârgîl.||ARABIC : Gawz el hind, Jauz al hind, Nârgîl.||BENGALI : Daab, Naarakel (Narkel), Naarakela, Narikel.||BULGARIAN : Кокос Kokos.||CHINESE : Ke ke ye zi (Taiwan), Ye zi, Ye shu.||ESTONIAN : Kookospalm.||FINNISH : Kookospähkinä, Kookospalmu.||FRENCH : Noix de coco, Cocotier||GERMAN : Kokos, Kokosnuß, Kokosnuss, Kokospalme.||HINDI : Naariyal (Nariyal), Naariyal kaa per (plant), Khopar.||INDONESIA : Kelapa||ITALIAN : Cocco, Noce di cocco, Palma del cocco.||JAPANESE : Koko yashi, Koko yashi, Natsume yashi.||KHMER : Doung.||KOREAN : K′o k′o neos.||LAOTIAN : Kok mak phao.||MARATHI : Naaral.||PORTUGUESE : Coco, Coco da Bahia, Coco da India, Coqueiro, Noz de coco.||RUSSIAN : Kokos, Kokos orekhonosnmi, Kokosobaia pal′ma.||SANSKRIT: Narekela, Sadaphala, Trinadruma, Dridhaphala.||SPANISH : Coco, Cocotero, Nuez de coco, Palma de coco, Palmera de coco.||THAI : Maphrao, Ma phrao on, Maak muu.||VIETNAMESE : Dừa.</vernacular>
		<properties>Coconut is one of the most useful plants in the world, providing a multitude of uses, from arrack to food staple, sugar to vinegar, fibers and fodder, thatching and lumber, and virgin coconut oil among many others. In addition, it yield 3 to 4 tons of copra (nut meat) per hectare and over two tons of oil. Coconut is an unarmed, erect, tall palm reaching a height of 25 meters. Trunk is stout, 30 to 50 centimeters in diameter, thickened at the base; marked with annular scars. Leaves are crowded at the apex of the trunk, 3.5 to 6 meters long, with a stout petiole, 1 meter or more in length. Leaflets are bright green, numerous, linear-lanceolate, flaccid, 60 to 100 centimeters long. Spadix is about 1 meter long, erect, drooping, straw-colored, simply branched. Male flowers are small and yellowish with small, ovate, valvate sepals and oblong, valvate petals. Female flowers are much larger, rounded, with imbricate sepals and shorter convolute petals. Fruit is variable in size, shape and color, obovoid to subglobose, often obscurely 3-angled, 15 to 25 centimeters long. Endosperm forms a thick white layer of fleshy fibrous substance adherent to the membranous testa which is adherent to the stony-black shell. The shell is covered by a fibrous husk. The embryo is opposite one pore.</properties>
		<usage>Myriads of use in the traditional systems worldwide: abscesses, asthma, baldness, burns and bruises,, cough and colds, kidney stones, scabies, ulcers, among many others.||Constipation: Take 1 to 2 tablespoons of gata (cream).||Dandruff: Massage oil on scalp, leave overnight, and wash hair.||Diarrhea and/or vomiting: Drink water of young fruit, as tolerated. Water from the young coconut has been used as a substitute for dextrose infusion in emergent situations during World War II.||Dry skin: Apply oil and massage into affected area.||Young roots astringent for sore throats.||Ash of bark used for scabies.||In New Guinea, young leaves chewed to a past and applied to cuts to stop the bleeding.||In Java used for dysentery and other intestinal complaints.||In Amboinia oil used as vermifuge.||In Jamaica, used for coughs.||Malays use poultice of roots in syphilis and gonorrhea; also, for rheumatism.||In India, young roots employed as astringent gargle for sore throat. Also, boiled with ginger and salt, used in fevers.||In the Gold Coast, bark used for curing toothache and earache.||In Nigeria, coconut water twice daily prescribed for treatment of diabetes.||In India ash of the bark used as dentrifice and as antiseptic. Ash is also used for scabies. The soft, downy, light-brown substance on the lower surface of the leaves used as styptic. Husk used in the treatment of tapeworms; in Punjab and Cashmere, used for throat inflammation. The tar obtained from burning the shell considered rubefacient; used for ringworm, itches and other parasitic infections.||In India, a toddy-poultice (fresh toddy and rice flour) used as application for gangrenous ulcerations, indolent ulcers, and carbuncles. Heating coconut shells yield an oil that is used for ringworm infections.||In Malaya. ash obtained from the coconut shell used for swellings, pains in the stomach, and for rheumatism. Coconut water is also used as diuretic.||In Mexico, coconut water used as diuretic and anthelmintic.||Roots used for strengthening the gums.||In Brazil, husks used in the treatment of diarrhea and arthritis.||Decoction of ground roots drunk in cases of small pox.||Flowers reported to be astringent; chewed in immature state for gonorrhea. Flowers have also been used for diabetes, dysentery, leprosy and urinary discharges.||In Mexico, decoction of the fibers of the trunk used as diuretic.||Tar obtained from burning the shell is used for toothache.||Water is fed to infants with diarrhea.||In emergencies, water has been used as intravenous drips. Anecdotal reports of use during cholera epidemics.</usage>
		<availability>Ubiquitous in the rural landscape; common cultivation as a plantation tree.||Commerce of coconut oil capsules, virgin coconut oil.</availability>
	</item>
</herbal>