<herbal>
	<item>
		<name>Lagundi</name>
		<sci_name>Vitex negundo||Vitex leucoxylon||Vitex arborea||Vitex bicolor||Vitex paniculata</sci_name>
		<common_name>Dabtan (If.)||Dangla (Ilk.)||Kamalan (Tag.)||Lagundi (Ibn., Tag., Bik., P. Bis.)||Liñgei (Bon.)||Limo-limo (Ilk.)||Sagarai (Bag.)||Turagay (Bis.)||Chinese chastetree (Engl.)||Five-leaved chaste tree (Engl.)||Huang jing zi (Chin.)||Agno-casto (Spanish)</common_name>
		<properties>Lagundi is an erect, branched tree or shrub, 2 to 5 meters high. Leaves are usually 5-foliate, rarely with 3 leaflets only, and palmately arranged. Leaflets are lanceolate, entire, 4 to 10 centimeters long, slightly hairy beneath, and pointed at both ends, the middle leaflets being larger than the others, and distinctly stalked. Flowers are numerous, blue to lavender, 6 to 7 millimeters long, borne in terminal inflorescences (panicles) 10 to 20 centimeters long. Calyx is hairy, and 5-toothed. Corolla is densely hairy in the throat, and the middle lobe of the lower lip is longest. Fruit is a succulent drupe, globose, black when ripe, about 4 millimeters in diameter.</properties>
		<usage>Decoction of leaves used externally for cleaning ulcers and internally for flatulence. Also used as a lactagogue and emmenagogue.||Decoction of bark, tops and leaves used as antigastralgic.||Leaves used in aromatic baths; also as insectifuge.||Vapor bath prepared with the plant used for treatment of febrile, catarrhal, and rheumatic affections.||Decoction of leaves used as warm bath by women suffering with after-pains in the puerperal period. Also used as baths for new born children.||Seeds are boiled in water and eaten or the water drunk to prevent the spread of toxin from bites of poisonous animals.||Infusion of seeds used for disinfecting wounds and ulcers.||Infusion of seeds in wine used for dropsy.||Pounded leaves applies on the forehead and temples for headaches.||Leaf decoction for fever, headache, toothache, cough, asthma.||Root used as tonic, febrifuge and expectorant.||Fruit used as nervine, cephalic, and emmenagogue.||Tincture of root bark used for irritable bladder and for rheumatism.||Powdered root used for piles as demulcent; also for dysentery.||Root used for dyspepsia, colic, rheumatism, worms, boils, and leprosy.||Flowers are used for diarrhea, cholera, fever, and diseases of the liver; and also as cardiac tonic.||Powdered flowers and stalks are used for bleeding from the stomach and bowels.||Fruit used for headaches, catarrh, and watery eyes. Dried fruits are used as vermifuge.||Seeds are prepared as cooling mediing for skin diseases, leprosy, and inflammation of the mouth.||Oil prepared with the juice used for sinuses and scrofulous sores. Oil also used as a rubbing application to glandular or tubercular swelliings of the neck. Oil also used for treatment of sloughing wounds and ulcers.||Leaves used for reducing inflammatory and rheumatic swellings of the joints and testicular swelling associated with gonorrheal epididymitis and orchitis. Poultice of leaves also applied to sprained limbs, contusions, leech bites, etc. For these, fresh leaves in an earthen pot are heated over fire, and applied and applied as tolerated over the bruised parts. Leaves heated over fire are also applied with oil externally on wounds.||Pillow stuffed with leaves is placed under the head for relief of catarrh and headache. Dried leaves when smoked also used to relieve catarrh and headaches.||Decoction of leaves and long pepper used for catarrhal fever associated with head congestion and dullness of hearing.||Juice of leaves used to remove fetid discharges and worms from ulcers.||Plaster of leaves applied to enlarged spleens.||Folkloric preparations: (1) For fever and toothaches, boil 6 tbsp of the chopped leaves in 2 glasses of water for 15 minutes; strain and cool. Divide the decoction in 3 parts and take one part every 3-4 hours. Also, bruised leaves may be applied to forehead. (2) For asthma and cough: Take 1/4 of the decoction three times a day. (3) Aromatic bath or sponge bathing: Boil 4 handfuls of leaves in a pot of water for 5 minutes; use the lukewarm decoction for sponge bathing.||In Ayurveda and Unani, leaves and seeds used for rheumatism and joint inflammation. Decoction of leaves taken as a diuretic.||In Bangladesh, used for headaches, weakness, vomiting, malaria black fever.||In Indo-China, root decoction used for intermittent fevers.||In Sri Lanka, used for eye disease, toothache, rheumatism; used as tonic, carminative and vermifuge.</usage>
		<availability>Wild-crafted.||Commercial formulations: Tablets, capsules, oil, teas, and syrup. </availability>
	</item>
</herbal>