<herbal>
	<item>
		<name>Balimbing</name>
		<sci_name>Averrhoa carambola||Averrhoa pentandra</sci_name>
		<common_name>Balimbing (C. Bis., Bik., Sul., Tag.)||Balingbing (Bik., C. Bis.)||Balimbin (Tag.)||Blingbing (Tag.)||Daligan (Ilk.)||Dalihan (Ibn.)||Galañgan (P. Bis.)||Galuran (Ibn.)||Garahan (Bis.)||Garulan (Ibn.)||Malimbin (S. L. Bis.)||Sirinate (Ting.)||Carambola (Span.)||Caramba (Span.)||Country gooseberry (Engl.)||Five-corner fruit (Engl.)||Five fingers (Engl.)||Star fruit (Engl.)||Yang tao (Chin.)</common_name>
		<vernacular>CHINESE: Wu lian zi.||DUTCH : Fransman birambi.||FRENCH : Carambolier, Carambolier doux.||GERMAN : Karambole, Sternfrucht.||ITALIAN : Carambola.||COUNTRY: Gorenshi, Karanbora, Sutaaru furuutsu.||KHMER : Spu.||LAOTIAN : Nak fuang.||MALAY : Belimbing batu, Belimbing besi, Belimbing manis, Belimbing manis, Belimbing pessegi, Belimbing sayur, Belimbing saji.||PORTUGUESE : Caramboleiro, Camerunga (Brazil), Limas de Cayena.||RUSSIAN: Karambola.||SANSKRIT : Karmaranga.||SPANISH : Arbol de pepino, Carambola, Carambolera, Carambolero, Tamarindo chino, Pepino de la India, Tamarindo dulce.||THAI: Ma fuang (Ma fueang, Ma fueng), Sa bue.||VIETNAMESE : Khế, Khế chua, Khế thái lan, Quả khế.</vernacular>
		<properties>Balimbing is a small tree growing to a height of 6 meters or less. Leaves are pinnate, about 15 centimeters long. Leaflets are smooth, usually in 5 pairs, ovate to ovate-lanceolate, the upper ones about 5 centimeters long and the lower ones smaller. Panicles are small, axillary and bell-shaped, 5 to 6 millimeters long. Calyx is reddish purple. Petals are purple to bright purple, often margined with white. Fruit is fleshy, green to greenish yellow, about 6 centimeters long, with 5 longitudinal, sharp and angular lobes. Seeds are arillate.</properties>
		<usage>Decoction of leaves used for aphthous stomatitis and angina.||In Tonkin, flowers are used as vermifuge.||Boiled flowers used to expel worms: 50 gms to a pint of boiling water; drunk in normal doses.||Malays use a poultice of crushed shoots or leaves used externally for headaches, chickenpox, and ringworm.||The Chinese and Annamites use the flowers for cutaneous affections; also use the fruit as an eye salve for ophthalmic affections.||Leaves applied externally for fevers.||Fruit syrup used as cooling drink for fevers.||Decoction of leaves and fruit used to arrest vomiting.||Fruit is laxative; also used for hematemesis, melena and other forms of hemorrhages.||Decoction of fruit, 50 gms to a pint of boiling water, 4-5 glasses a day used for bleeding piles.||Juice of fresh fruit for affections of the eyes.||Seed is used for asthma and colic: Powdered seeds, 10 gms to a cup of warm water, drunk 4 times daily.||In Brazil, used for headaches, eczema, vomiting, coughing and hangovers. Also, used as appetite stimulant, diuretic, antidiarrheal, and febrifuge.||In India, the ripe fruit is used to stop hemorrhages and relieve hemorrhoidal bleeding. Khasi tribe of Meghalaya use the ripe fruit in the treatment of jaundice.||The dried fruit or juice used for fevers.||Plant used as reproductive organ stimulant for both males and females. In females it is used to increase the flow of milk and menstrual fluid. It acts as an emmenagogue; sometimes used as abortive.||In Ayurveda, ripe fruit is considered tonic and digestive; causes biliousness. Dried fruit is used for fevers.||Seed regarded as narcotic, anodyne, emetic, and emmenagogue. Seed powder, in doses of 1/2 to 3 drams or as watery infusion, considered a good anodyne in asthma, colic, and jaundice.</usage>
		<availability>Wild-crafted.||Limited backyard cultivation.</availability>
	</item>
</herbal>